片名：战略高手
山托斯银行
- You have a loan app? Wonderful.
-Terrific.
你有贷款申请书？好极了
前几天我和太太吃晚饭 刚结婚
How can I help you, sir?
我是否能为你效劳？罗莉塔
看到没有，哪个和经理讲话手提箱开着的人
See the man talking
to your bank manager has his case open?
That's Mr. Gwendon,
one of our assistant managers.
那是戈登先生,助理经理之一
Our manager is Mr. Schoen.
He's not in today.
我们经理是萧恩先生但是他今天不在
- You see the man with the briefcase?
-Yes.
你看到那个带手提箱的人？是
That's my partner. He has a gun in there.
那是我的同伙，他有枪
If you don't do exactly what I say,
如果你不照我说的做
I'm look at my partner and he'll shoot
Mr. Gwendon between the eyes.
我看一眼我的同伙他就会朝戈登先生的眉心开枪
(SIGHS)
好
行，去拿个大的信封 装好100, 50, 20钞票
Take one of those big envelopes and pack
it with 100s, 50s and 20s.
Nothing with bank straps or rubber bands.
No dye packs. No bait money.
不要银行的袋子和橡皮筋、染色包，和有记号的钱
Start with the second drawer,
then the one over there.
从第二个抽屉开始，然后那一个
It's okay. Come on, Loretta.
Key's right there next to you.
好，快，罗莉塔 钥匙就在旁边
对了
No bills off the bottom of the drawer,
please.
不要最下边的
This your first time being robbed?
这是你第一次被抢？
你做得蛮好，保持笑容 不要看起来被抢的样子
You're doing great. Just smile so
you don't look like you're being held up.
你笑得很美
You got a very pretty smile.
Give me the 20s. I'll take those.
给我20元的，我要那些
不错，放到我的口袋里
I'll put those in my pocket.
There you go.
对了
I haven't had to signal my partner,
and that's good.
我还没有和我同伙打暗号
He'll wait until I'll leave,
to make sure you don't set off the alarm.
他会等我离开并确定你没按警铃
If you do, he'll shoot
Mr. Gwendon between the eyes.
如果你那么做，他就会对准戈登先生的眉心开枪
好 这样够了，罗莉塔
I think that'll do it, Loretta.
Thank you. Have a nice day.
谢谢，祝你顺利
你也是
You too.
她很可爱，不是吗？
She's cute, isn't she?
她看起来很甜
She seems very nice.
那是谁？
Who was that?
(IGNITION GRINDING)
No,no,no.
要命，真要命
(PUMPING GAS PEDAL)
狗娘养的
Fuck!
操!操!
I think you flooded it.
Get out of the car, sir.
我想你加太多油了 先生，请下车
(CHUCKLES)
你要听个笑话吗？闭嘴！下车
- You wanna hear a funny story?
-Shut up and get out of the car!
好吧
Yeah. Okay.
格雷兹监狱
贝格雷兹，佛罗里达州
(CHEERING)
走, 走, 走!
(APPLAUDING)
(INAUDIBLE)
You want something, Foley?
那要干嘛？弗里
Some fellas are going out of here.
Want to know where and when?
有人要逃走，想要知道何时何地吗？
- How many?
-I expect you to look out for me.
有多少人？我要你把风
Okay. How many going out?
好！有多少人出去？
- I hear six.
-When?
听说六个 什么时候？
- Tonight.
-You know who they are?
今晚 你知道有谁？
Yes, but I'm not telling you yet.
知道，但我不能告诉你
Meet me in the chapel before lockdown.
上锁前在教堂见我
你好 我爱你
I love you, baby.
Tonight's the big night. You excited?
今晚有大事，你兴奋吗？
- It's Super Bowl Sunday, okay?
-You moved it up.
是超级杯星期日？你提前了？
- Why do you think that?
-I saw you running this morning.
你为何那么想？ 今天早上我看你跑步
Sticking to your routine,
只是例行公事
but you only did a couple of miles,
instead of your usual five.
但你只跑了几里，不是平常的5里
Saving yourself for the big event.
What happened? Finished early?
好省点力气做大事  什么事？早做完了
You see those posts out there?
你看到那里的柱子吗？
They're putting up another fence
15 feet back the fence that's already there.
他们要在原来的铁丝网后15尺的地方再筑一道
So if on Super Bowl Sunday,
they have that fence built
如果在星期日超级杯前铁丝网已经筑好了
那我们就要在挖个九到十天
then we have to dig, what,
another nine, ten days?
是啊  我想不会
I don't think so.
So tonight, when it's dark,
I'm out of here. You can come, Foley.
所以今天天黑后我要逃出去  你可以来，弗里
I appreciate the offer, and it's tempting,
谢谢提议，倒是非常诱人
but it's a long run,
a hundred miles to Miami?
什么？到迈阿密要100里？
I'm too old to be trying a stunt like that.
我太老了，做不了这种特技
你出去就寄明信片来
Send me a postcard when you get out.
迈阿密
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Adele Delisi speaking.
我是阿黛尔德丽西
你要接受杰克·弗里打来的由你付款的电话吗
OPERATOR: Will you accept a collect call
from Jack Foley?
I'll accept.
我接受
- Adele, how you doing?
-Hey, bank robber.
阿黛尔，你好  嘿，抢银行的
要听忠告吗？  下一次把引擎开着
Want some advice?
Next time, keep the engine running.
- That's funny!
-What do you want?
呵呵！好好笑啊  你要什么？杰克
阿黛尔，下星期天超级杯派对……
That Super Bowl party
that was for next Sunday,
it's tonight at 6:30.
他们改变了日期，是今晚6：30
你说过电话不会被监听  原则上不会
- You said one-time calls aren't monitored.
- Not as a rule.
So why don't you just tell
me what you're talking about.
那就告诉我你在说什么
- Miss Smarty Mouth, in the free world.
- What's free about it?
在自由国度的快嘴小姐  自由怎么样？
我在找工作
I'm lookin' for work.
- What about Mandrake the Magician?
- Emile the Amazing.
曼卓魔术师如何？ 神奇的伊米
He fired me.
Hired a younger girl. A redhead.
他炒了我鱿鱼 雇了个年轻的红发的女郎
I'm calling because they changed the date.
我打电话是因他们改了日期
It's tonight at 6:30, a few hours from now.
今晚6:30，还有几小时
- You tell Buddy.
- And the guy driving the other car?
和巴蒂联络  和在另一车的家伙
- What guy?
-As you have so much luck with cars,
哪个？ 因为你老搞不定车子
Buddy thought it might be better
to bring two.
巴蒂想要带两辆车比较稳
He got a guy he says you know
from Lompoc.
他说找了个你在兰坡认识的家伙
- Glenn somebody.
- Glenn Michaels.
葛兰什么的  葛兰麦克
Uh-huh. That's him. Buddy said Glenn
thinks you guys are real cool.
是他，巴蒂说葛兰认为你们这一伙真酷
阿黛尔？ 呀？
Tell Buddy if Glenn's wearing sunglasses,
I'll step on them.
告诉巴蒂如果葛兰戴太阳眼镜，我就踩烂他
- I might not even take them off first.
-I'll sure do that.
我甚至一开始就不拿下来  好的，我会的
Okay, hon. Now, try not to get shot. Bye.
小心不要被射死，拜拜
嗨
Ma'am. Let me help you.
夫人，我来帮你
A lady like you
shouldn't be carrying groceries.
像你这样的漂亮女士，不应该搬杂货
Let a man do that for you.
该让男人来帮你做
我没要你帮忙，不要期望小费
I didn't ask for your help,
so don't expect a tip.
没问题，夫人，那我就开走你的车
That's okay, Ma'am. I'll just take your car.
生日快乐
MARSHALL: Happy birthday.
又是一套香奈尔的套装
Did you fit another Chanel suit in here?
Something much better. Open it.
有更棒的，打开它
Oh, my God. It's beautiful.
天啊！真漂亮
这是……  是西格380
-It's a...
-SIG Sauer 380.
- Right.
-I love it!
对  我真喜欢
Thanks, Dad.
谢谢，爸
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
- Some more coffee?
-I can't.
再来些咖啡？  我不要了
I have to go out to Glades,
then I'm meeting Ray Nicolet at 10:00.
我要去格雷兹  十点跟雷尼可见面
Which one is that? The A.T.F. guy?
哪个？ 在联邦火器局那个？
He's with the F.B.l. now.
He switched over.
他现在联邦调查局，调过来了
- He's still married, though.
-Technically. They're separated.
但他已结婚  在法律上是，他们已分居
- He moved out then?
-He's about to.
他搬出来了吗？ 差不多了
那他们还不算分居  能不能不谈这些？
- Then they're not separated.
-Can we not talk about this?
- What are you doing at Glades?
-Serving a summons and complaint.
你去格雷兹干什么？  送传票和控诉状
Some con doing life
doesn't like macaroni and cheese.
有个终身监禁的罪犯不喜欢起司通心粉
So, he files suit, says he has
no choice on what they serve,
所以他提出控诉说，他不能选择他们的服务
which violates his civil rights.
这侵犯了他的人权
You can step in, work for me
as one of my investigators.
你可以到我这里做我的调查员
不，谢了
- No, thanks.
-You used to like it.
你以前喜欢做  爸
You'd meet doctors, lawyers.
They're all fine, if they're divorced.
你可以和那些律师、医生约会，只要他们离了婚
凯伦，为什么把时间那浪费在牛仔警察身上
Karen, why waste your time
on some cowboy cop
who drinks and cheats on his wife?
他酗酒又不尊重老婆
That's how those hot shots are.
他们就是这种人
I really gotta go.
我真要走了
We don't talk much anymore.
我们不像以前那样聊得多了
How about I come over Sunday
and we watch the Super Bowl together?
我星期天过来，一起看超级杯？
I'd like that.
太好了
Thanks for the gun, Dad.
爸，谢谢那支枪
They dug a tunnel underneath you.
他们在你下面挖了一条地道
I don't hear anything.
Where's the tunnel come out?
我没听说，地道从那里出来？
Fourth post from the guard tower.
从守望塔第四根柱子
I don't see nothing.
我什么也没看见
Just keep watching.
继续看
(DIALING)
OPERATOR: F.B.l.
How may I direct your call?
联邦调查局，请问找哪位？
This is Karen Sisco again for Ray Nicolet.
我是凯伦西斯柯，找雷尼可
Hold, please.
请稍等
Yeah.
好
占线，你要留言吗？
The line is busy. You want his voice mail?
不用了，我等一下再打
No, forget it. I'll call back later.
- All right.
- Than ks.
好的   谢谢
I still don't see anything.
还是没看到
You will directly.
你马上就看到了
OFFICER: Wait a minute!
等一下
尼古丁口香糖
(DIGGING)
What the fuck?
见鬼！
(HONKING)
Two men by the fence!
铁丝网旁边有两个人！
(SIRENS WAILING)
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
What the hell is she doing?
她在搞什么鬼？
别动！举起手来！
Stop! Get your hands in the air!
(GUARDS SHOUTING)
地道里没人
Tunnel's clear.
Seal up the north face.
- GUARD: What happened?
-What do you think? Got a jail break!
发生什么事？ 你说呢？有人越狱了
- The Cubans are out in the cane.
-Don't point that at me. Hey, Buddy.
古巴人在哪里？别对着我 嘿！巴蒂！
- It's okay, we're the good guys.
-What are you doing here?
别紧张，我们是好人  你在这里干什么？
她只是个女孩，为什么用枪？
You're just a girl. Why the shotgun?
I'm a federal marshal. You're under arrest.
我是联邦警察，你被捕了！可能都是
Why don't we talk about this later?
我们等会再说吧
Watch your head.
小心你的头
I'm in. Let's go!
我进来了，走吧
你舒服吗？太挤了
- JACK: You comfy?
-If I could have a little more room...
Well, there isn't any.
没地方了
There's a lot of shit in here. Handcuffs.
这里有好东西，手铐啊
这罐子里是什么？
What's in this can?
That's for your breath.
Squirt some in your mouth.
除口臭的，挤一点到你嘴巴里
那是美斯，不是吗？
That's Mace, isn't it?
(MEN SHOUTING)
好吧！你，去……
嘿，你的枪呢？你的手枪
Where's your gun? Your pistol?
在车里，我的包里
In my bag, in the car.
Boy, it stunk in there.
要命，这里真臭
我想是的，你把我爸给我的值900元的套装弄坏了
I believe it. You're ruining
a $900 suit my dad gave me.
It went great with that 12-gauge.
它和那只12口径的枪很配
Why would someone like you
become a marshal?
像你这种人怎么会当法警
- To go after guys like you.
-What was that?
专门抓你这种人  那是什么意思？
Guys like me? Let me tell you something.
像我这种人！让我告诉你吧
Even though I've been celibate lately,
I'm not forcing myself on you.
虽然我近来单身，但是我不是非要缠着你不可
- I've never done that.
-You won't have time.
我从没做过  你不会有时间做
We hit a roadblock, they run the car
and find out who it belongs to.
碰到路障，他们查车后就会知道这是谁的车了
I doubt they'll get one set up in time.
If they do,
即使他们要设的话，我怀疑他们能否及时设一个
they'll be lookin' for two Latin fellas,
not a big black guy.
他们要找两个拉丁人，而不是个黑大个.
他真是你的好兄弟，如此拿自己来牺牲
KAREN". He must be quite a pal,
to risk his own ass like this.
JACK: Buddy? He's a good guy.
巴蒂，他是个好家伙
When we jailed together, he would call
his sister every week, without fail.
我们一起坐牢时，他每周一定打电话给他姐姐
She's a born-again Christian.
She does bookkeeping for a televangelist.
她是重生的基督徒，给电视布道家记账
He'd call her up, confess his sins.
他会打电话向她忏悔
Tell her whatever bank he'd robbed.
告诉他抢过的银行
巴蒂是他的名字吗？
KAREN". Is Buddy his given name?
JACK: The one I gave him, yeah.
对！我给他取得
KAREN". What's your name?
你叫什么？
It'll be in the paper tomorrow anyway.
明天看报就知道了
Jack Foley. You've probably heard of me.
杰克弗里，你恐怕听过
- Why? Are you famous?
-The time I was convicted in California,
为什么，你很有名吗？我在加州被判刑时
the F.B.l. told me that I'd robbed
more banks than anybody in the computer.
调查局说我抢银行的纪录比谁都多
- How many was that?
-I don't really know.
多少次？我真的不知道
我18岁时开始替我叔叔卡利和他搭档开车
I started when I was 18, I drove
for my uncle Cully, and his partner, Gus.
你是说你半辈子都在牢里
Basically you're saying
you spent half your life in prison.
Basically, yeah. If I go back, I do 30 years.
对，如果再被逮住，要关30年
- You imagine looking at that?
-I don't have to. I don't rob banks.
你能想象吗？我不用想，我又不抢银行
JACK: You don't seem all that scared.
你好像一点都不怕
我当然怕 看不出来
- Of course I am.
-You don't act like it.
Do you want me to scream?
你要我大叫吗？
That wouldn't help much anyway.
那也起不了作用
我打算坐在这里，等你自己搞砸
I'm just gonna sit here, take it
easy, and wait for you to screw up.
(JACK CHUCKLES)
JACK: You sound like my ex-wife.
听起来像我前妻
- You were married?
-For about a year, give or take a few days.
你结过婚  一年左右
It's not like we didn't get along.
We had fun. We just
我们相处得不错，只是……
didn't have that thing, you know,
没有那种……
that spark. Gotta have that.
激情，那很重要  嗯哼
Uh-huh.
- We still talk, though.
-Sure.
尽管我们仍在说话  是吗？
KAREN: This is not gonna end well.
These things never do.
你是不会有好下场的  做这种事永远都不会有
If I'm going to get shot
it's gonna be in the street,
我要死也想被人打死在大街上
not off a goddamn fence.
不想死在牢里
You must really see yourself
as some kind of Clyde Barrow.
你真以为你是什么克莱贝罗
You mean, of "Bonnie and Clyde"?
你是指邦尼和克莱  是的
The part in the movie where they get
shot, Warren Beatty and
电影中他们中弹 华伦比提和……
费唐 娜薇  费唐 娜薇，yeah.
Faye Dunaway.
- I like her in that movie about TV.
-Network. She was good.
我喜欢她演的“电视网”演得真好
That guy who says he won't
take any more shit.
那家伙说他再不吃那套
Peter Finch.
彼特 芬奇  Yeah! 彼特 芬奇
“我已经火大了，我不会吃你那套”
"I'm mad as hell, and I'm not
gonna take any more of your shit!"
In the part where they get shot,
I remember
在他们中枪的那一节，我记得我一直在想……
如果你别无选择的时候，这个结局也不算太坏
thinking that it wouldn't be
such a bad way to go, if you had to.
(SIRENS WAILING)
你很会和人聊天
JACK: You sure are easy to talk to.
I was thinking, if we met
under different circumstances,
如果我们在不同的场合下遇到
if you were in a bar and
I came up and we started talking,
你在酒吧，我出现，我们交谈
然后呢？没有了
- I wonder what would happen.
-Nothing.
- If you didn't know who I was.
-You'd probably tell me.
如果你不知道我是谁  你可能会告诉我
- But if circumstances were different...
-You have got to be kidding.
如果场合不同……你在开玩笑
是, 是
Another Faye Dunaway movie I liked
was Three Days of the Condor.
我喜欢另一部费唐娜薇演的电影是《三日兀鹰》
劳伯瑞夫年轻时拍的那部
The one with Robert Redford
when he was young.
是
I never thought it made sense though.
那部电影一点意思都没有
The way they got together so quick.
他们那么快就好上了
Really?
是嘛？
I mean, romantically.
很浪漫  嗯哼
可是……
JACK: Here we go. Where the hell are we?
又停了
我们现在在哪里?
BUDDY: Turnpike. Glenn's above us
with the other car.
公路收费口，葛兰在上面另一辆车里
快出来! 背过身举起手
- JACK: Hop on out.
-Turn around and get your hands up!
快出来!背过身举起手
(GUNSHOTS FIRING)
BUDDY: We may as well leave her.
We're leavin' the car
别管她，反正我们也不要这辆车了
and we gotta leave her someplace.
我们总要把她甩了
- She's coming with us.
-Jesus, what were you doing in there?
她得跟著我们  天啊，你在那里搞什么?
找名字  找过了
- Looking for a name.
-I already looked.
Her name is Karen Sisco.
Like the Cisco Kid, only spelled different.
她叫凯伦西思科，像席司科孩童，拼法不同
(SIRENS WAILING)
凯伦?
凯伦，你要老实一点
Karen? You be a good girl now.
I'm gonna open up the trunk.
我要打开后车盖了
Hey! You're putting holes in your car!
喂! 喂! 喂!你在往自己车上打窟窿
I'm not leavin' you. I'll open the trunk.
Drop your pistol out.
我不会把你扔在这里，我要开后车盖，你把枪扔出来
If you shoot, Buddy's got your shotgun.
He'll shoot back.
巴蒂有你的猎枪，你要开枪的话，他会射回去
我拦不住他，就看你自己了
I can't stop him. So it's up to you.
别开枪!是葛兰
GLENN: Hey!
Don't! It's Glenn!
Fuck! Jack. Good to see you.
妈的，杰克，很高兴见到你
What are you guys shooting at?
你们在射谁?
- Do we need him?
-The cop saw this car.
我们要他吗?警察见过这辆车
He might tie it to the break
and turn around.
他可能会起疑心再调回头 好吧
- Hey, Studs. We didn't recognize you.
-Hey, "Studs."
嘿，小伙子，我们没认出你  嘿，“小伙子 ”
从兰坡出来後就没有听过混得怎么样?
I haven't heard that since Lompoc.
What's going on?
Nothing.
没怎么样
Karen. Are you coming out?
凯伦，你要出来吗?
(COCKING)
- You hear that?
-Okay.
听到了吗？好吧
—听到了吗？好吧
算你赢，杰克
You win, Jack.
When you get your suit cleaned,
send me the bill.
衣服乾洗完后 帐单寄给我
I'll send it to you at Glades.
我会寄到葛雷兹去
Did you crawl through a sewer?
Who're you?
你是不是刚从阴沟洞里爬出来?你是谁?
- Take your sunglasses off.
-I see better with them on.
摘下墨镜  戴著看得更清楚
I'll throw them off the overpass
while they're still on your head.
小心我把你和墨镜一起扔到天桥上去
- Wait in the car.
-We're in civilization now, so ease up.
等在车里 文明社会里，说话客气点
I'm sorry. Wait in the car, please.
Take her, put her in the back.
对不起，请你在车里等，带上她，放在后座!
- In the trunk?
-In the backseat!
后车厢？后坐！
过来!因为我要……把外套给我!
- Come now, 'cause I got to do...
-Give me yourjacket.
我需要干净衣服
Somebody forgot
to bring the clean clothes.
BUDDY: They're at Glades, in the Cadillac.
干净衣服在凯迪拉克车里
You decided to jump
into the trunk of her car.
是你自己要跳进她的后车箱
You can blame me if you want.
I don't mind.
你可以怪我，我不介意
—给你：我要告诉你……
- What's your problem?
-Why did you bring Glenn?
你有什么毛病?你为什么叫葛兰来
- The score was his idea.
Jdea?
这件事是他的主意  他?
He has a vacant lot for a head.
他没有大脑的
他以为他可以用这种口气跟我说话
He thinks he can talk to me like that?
“把外套给我”我坐在这里等了半个钟头
"Give me yourjacket." I have been
sitting here for a half-hour,
防备著警察 你以为那是好玩的?
watching out for cops.
You think that's fun?
我得钻进灌木丛……
I had to go in the bushes
to smoke a joint, just so I could,
you know?
抽根大麻，这样我才能…你知道吗?
(WHISTLES)
GLENN: Yep. I got something big lined up
up north.
对 我在北部有大计划
These guys wouldn't even know
about it, if it wasn't for me.
如果没有我，这些家伙怎么可能知道
- Every time he talks, I want to punch him.
-He's not the problem.
他一讲话我就想揍他  他不是问题
Why are we bringing her with us?
你干什么要把她带著?
葛兰
You don't remember me, do you?
你不记得我了吗?
我从未进过葛雷兹，如果你是这个意思的话
I was never at Glades,
if that's what you're thinking.
That's not what I'm thinking.
我不是这个意思  是
But you're sure we've met?
但你肯定我们见过?
Last fall.
去年秋天
I drove you from Palm Beach county jail
to the federal courthouse twice.
我押著你从棕榈滩县监狱到联邦法院，两次
You're Glenn Michaels.
你是葛兰麦克
I never forget anybody
I've cuffed and shackled.
我从不忘记我逮过的任何人
Let's see if we can work this out, Glenn.
让我们来想想办法，葛兰
Do we have a gun in the car?
车里有枪吗？
Oh, shit! I remember you!
见鬼，我记起来了
Foley's won't make it.
If he goes down, you go with him.
弗理不会有好下场的，他完蛋，你也跟著完蛋
- I can understand if you guys are close...
-No, we're not.
你们关系近的话我倒能了解  不，我跟他根本不熟
- But, I'm helping him.
-Now wait a minute.
但我现在是在帮他  等一下，葛兰
Have you helped him?
你以前帮过他吗?
At this point, I doubt you could be charged
with aiding a fugitive.
目前我想你还应该不会被控“越狱共犯”的罪名
So you still have a choice.
你还有机会
You want to take her to my place, get
cleaned up, come out
你想把她带到我那里洗干净，抹上科龙水……
with your aftershave on, and she goes,
"I had you all wrong."
出来，然後她说“原来我看错你了 ”
I just wanna talk to her again.
我只是想同她再聊几句
See what it would be like
under normal circumstances.
看看在正常情况下会怎样
It's too late for that.
太迟了
He wants to get out of here,
and I don't blame him.
他想摆脱我们，我不怪他
两年前
在兰坡联邦监狱
If the ref don't call it soon,
they'll take this cat out in a body bag.
如果裁判再不叫停的话，那小子要被装在裹尸袋抬出去了
Do you know why they call him "Snoopy"?
你知道他们为什么叫他“史努比?”
He used to be Maurice "Mad Dog" Miller,
他以前叫“疯狗”莫瑞
back when he was a pro.
当他还是职业拳手的时候
Now you pet him, he goes down.
现在你轻拍他，他就倒下来
难以置信  天啊!
- I don't believe it!
-Oh, my!
(CROWD JEERING)
胡闹!胡闹
Yeah, you're the man.
好，你行
Guy's bragging he won a thrown fight.
那小子到处吹他
Fucking pathetic.
赢了一场做假的拳赛
Dangerous is what it is.
他要倒楣了
- Who's the bald dude?
-Richard Ripley.
那个秃子是谁?  理查瑞利
The Wall Street guy?
华尔街的?
He ripped off so many guys, he's called
Dick the Ripper.
他骗了好多人的钱，浑号骗子迪克
I didn't recognize him without his rug.
没戴假发我都认不出他
- What's his bid?
-Three years.
他被判多少年?三年
You guys on the bench?
你们被罚了吗?
Three years, fined $50 million
and wrote them a fucking check.
三年，罚金五千万，他妈的就写了张支票
就这样
Just like that.
Fifty mill, signed his name.
五千万，签一个名而已
Didn't even... Okay, a little help.
还没有…对了…帮个小忙
Okay, heavy!
够了，太重
Heavy! Come on!
天!太重了
(GROANING)
With the glare out here, you couldn't read
the numbers on the weights.
阳光刺眼，看不清上面的数字
我知道了
I had it.
- How do you know he wrote a check?
-He told me.
你怎么知道他写了张支票？他告诉我的
We work laundry together.
我们一起在洗衣房当差
那家伙真他妈的爱说
Guy loves to fucking talk.
He loves to talk.
He talked to the U.S. Attorney.
他爱说：他告诉联邦检察官
Rolled over on the snitches
he did business with.
他被那些与他做生意的人告发了
有哪个家伙能拿出五千万的支票
Any guy who can write
a check for $50 million,
他说什么我都听
he says anything, I'm all fucking ears.
Guy tells me he's got
all this money in foreign banks.
他告诉我他把钱都存在外国银行
Plus, around
加上，大概……
five million in uncut diamonds
at his house.
他家里值五百万未加工的钻石
He said, quote,
他说
"That I can get my hands on it
at any time."
“我可以随时动这笔钱 ”
- Where does he live?
-GLENN: Detroit.
他住哪里？底特律
史努比米勒说未加工的钻石跟现金一样好处理
Snoopy Miller says that uncut diamonds
are as easy to move as cash.
Ever seen an uncut diamond?
见过未加工的钻石吗?
Looks just like a plain old rock.
就像一般石头
Wait, you think this guy's lying?
慢著，你以为他在说谎?
What do you think?
Use your head. A guy's got $5 million
你说呢?用你的大脑想一想如果他有五百万，
socked away, and he's gonna tell some
motormouth he meets in prison about it?
他会告诉你这样在监狱里的大嘴巴?
Oh, I see. You guys are cynical.
我就知道你们不会相信我
来了
Here it comes.
Keep on walking. Keep walking.
别停下，继续走
You don't wanna be
answering any questions.
你别回答任何问题
JACK: I'm just saying she wasn't scared.
我只是说她一点都不怕
BUDDY: Because she had her hand
on her gun.
因为她手里有手枪
JACK: You're just jealous
because you weren't in the trunk with her.
你是嫉妒你没有在后车箱跟她在一起
不是你  对了
BUDDY: You're right.
让我先把自己弄干净
First thing I'm gonna do is get this
mud off me.
喂
Hey.
凯伦
MARSHALL: Karen, honey?
凯伦，亲爱的?
凯伦
你说梦话
You were talking in your sleep.
What'd I say?
我说了甚么
“嘿，你自己 ”
"Hey, yourself."
喂
(KNOCKING)
喂，丹尼尔
(GROANS)
Daniel Burdon, F.B.l.
丹尼尔波顿，联邦调查局
Marshall Sisco, Karen's dad.
联邦警察西思柯，凯伦的父亲
Would you mind, waiting outside?
请你在外面等等
We have some business to do here.
我们有事要谈
I have to use the john anyway.
反正我要上厕所
对不起
I wanna be on the task force.
我要加入特勤小组 丹尼尔
嗯-
That's nice of you to offer, but
谢谢你的好意，但是……
I got all the help I can use right now.
我已有足够的人力
让我们谈一下你头上的包是怎么来的
Let's talk about
how you got that bump on your head.
Isn't that my file you're holding?
你手上拿的不是我的卷宗吗?
是的，但是我要听你亲口讲
Yes, but I want to hear it from you,
starting from when you grabbed the wheel.
从你和他抢驾驶盘开始
这是在那儿?
Where was this?
Coming to the Okeechobee exit.
快到欧基乔比出口的地方
- GLENN: Sit back!
-KAREN: Can you see with those glasses on?
坐好!你戴著墨镜，能看得到吗?
I'm fine! This is stupid.
我很好!这…真笨
These guys are gonna be
so disappointed in me.
这些家伙会对我很失望
You know what? If I wasn't stoned,
你知道吗？如果不是吸了大麻
there is no way you would have
talked me into this.
我才不会听你的
记住 过了桥就从这里出去
Get off at the exit right after that bridge.
我不会去自首
I am not turning myself in!
- Get off at that exit!
-What exit?
往那边开  哪边?
- That exit right there!
-Sit back!
那边的出口 坐好!
当我清醒时
KAREN". Next thing I knew,
paramedics were pulling me out of the car.
救护人员把我从车里拖出来
你还好
有几个问题我怀疑的是……
There's a couple of points I wonder about
concerning the two guys who grabbed you.
有关那两个捉你的家伙
Buddy, is it? And this fella Jack Foley.
是巴蒂?和这个家伙杰克弗理
The man must have robbed
over 200 banks in his time.
这个人起码已抢了200家银行
Really?
啊？
He told me he didn't
remember how many he robbed.
他告诉我他记不得抢了多少家
Then you talked to him.
那你和他谈过话
In the trunk, yeah.
在后车箱里，是啊
What'd you talk about?
你们谈甚么?
Different things.
各种事
Prison, movies.
监狱，电影
这家伙绑架你，你还跟他谈电影?
This fella holds you hostage,
you talk about movies?
It was an unusual experience.
这是个不平凡的经验
Foley made me think
of that fella Carl Tillman.
弗理让我想起卡尔提门
You were seeing him, it turns out
while he was robbing banks.
你去看时，他刚巧在抢银行
- Do you recall that?
-And what happened to Carl?
你记不记得?卡尔怎么了?
You shot him. But you
didn't shoot Foley or his friend.
你对他开枪 但是你没打弗理和他的朋友
They're unarmed. You had a shotgun
and you let them throw you in the trunk.
他们没带武器 你有散弹枪 却让他们把你丢进后车箱
You got your SIG in your hand.
你手上有西格手枪
你在报告中说你不能回头
You say in the report
that you couldn't turn around.
但是当车箱打开时
But when the trunk opened,
how come you didn't cap them then?
为什么你不打死他们?
What do you usually work on? Fraud?
Crooked bookkeepers?
你平常做什么？捉做手脚的簿记人员?
我在局里十五年，参加过各种不同的调查
I've been with the Bureau
15 years on all kinds of investigations.
曾经射杀过人没有？没有
- Ever shot a man?
-No.
- Ever been primary through the door?
-I have to qualify?
你有没有带头破门而入过?我还要资格审查?
You have to know
what you're talking about.
你必须知道你自己在说什么
(MARSHALL CHUCKLING)
We'll talk another time. All right?
下次再谈
I wonder why Foley put you in that second
car when he didn't need you anymore.
奇怪!为什么弗理在不需要你的时候还把你放进第二辆车……
You'll have to ask him that.
那你只有去问他自己了
- What the deal is, baby?
-Hi, Maurice.
谈个交易怎么样?嗨，莫瑞
我不知道  来敲敲手
- I don't know.
-Make a fist.
- There you go.
-Fuck it, man.
又来了  走开
Got your little fishies for you.
我拿到你要的金鱼了  好
Not so fast. Starting out, there's gonna be
a cost of living increase.
慢点 价钱涨了
什么？
我是因信用欺诈被抓进来的
Getting put in here for credit fraud
不过只是个小角色
I didn't really get no props for that.
但自从我在院子里捅了那个大嘴巴後
But ever since I shanked
that loudmouth pussy in the yard,
我的名声大涨
it's like my Dun and Broadstreet shot way
the fuck up.
Actually, it's Dun and Bradstreet.
变成大英雄了
Well, I've heard it both ways.
我都听说了
Point is, the price has gone up too.
最重要的是，价钱涨了
Get your black book out.
We got some business to talk about.
把你的黑册子拿出来我们要办正事
For the fishies...
What'd I say they was gonna be?
这些鱼，我以前讲的价钱是
两千  现在是三千
- Two thousand.
-Now they're three thousand.
- Come on...
什么…现在是三千
That saltwater shit you put in your eyes?
那些滴在你眼睛里的狗屎盐水
你叫它们什么?眼药水
- What do you call that?
-Bausch & Lomb.
Yeah, that Bauschie Lomb shit. That's 300.
那些狗屎眼药水，是三百块
- I need it.
-Yeah, you do. And that extra pillow.
我要  对，你要 另外那个枕头
I'm gonna get that for you,
but that's gonna be like five C's.
我会帮你搞到，但要五百块
- Five?
-JACK: Hey.
五百?
标志上说禁止讲话，你们不识字吗?
Sign says shut the fuck up,
or can't you fellas read?
你他妈的和谁讲话?
Who the fuck you talkin' to, man?
You got a problem over there, Foley?
弗理，你有什么问题吗?
This is the dumbest shakedown in
the history of dumb shakedowns.
这是我看过最笨的一个敲诈
Five hundred bucks for a pillow?
五百块一个枕头 对啊
- It does seem a little high.
-Shut up, Dick.
是有点太贵了  闭嘴，迪克
- Must be a nice pillow.
-Faux goose down.
一定是好枕头  高级鹅毛的
- But still...
-How much for your company at chow?
但是…你们一夥赚多少?
My company?
I'll watch this motherfucker's back.
我们一夥?我得看著这狗娘养的
- How much?
-That's a C-note.
多少?100块
Ripley, tell this guy to fuck off.
瑞利，叫这家伙滚开
Really?
真的？
Well, I don't know.
我不知道
If he kills you, he gets nothing.
他杀了你，什么也得不到
不必杀他，弗理
The man don't just have to die, Foley.
He could accidentally hurt himself
by falling on something hard.
他可能跌倒在硬东西上伤到自己
Like a shiv. Or my dick.
像刀或我的老二甚么的
I'll pay. I'll pay it. Don't worry.
我付钱 我付钱 别担心
如果他跌倒，史努比
If he falls on anything, Snoop,
他会很快被转监 快到你想不到
then they'll transfer him
faster than you can throw a fight
and you still get nothing.
你还是甚么也得不到
上次我查过
Last time I checked, man,
这与你无关
this shit didn't involve you.
出去抽根烟或甚么的
Go outside and
smoke a cigarette or some shit.
I don't smoke.
我不抽烟
You heard him.
Get your punk ass out of here.
你听到他啦 快滚吧
你惨了，那是海米
- Oh-oh.
-You fucked up. That's Himey.
Protege of mine. Ranked number 32
in the federal prison system.
我的保镖，这监狱的第32号狠人物
32？
对
- Thirty-two?
-That's right.
- Out of, what, 20?
-Kick his ass.
在多少，20个人里面?扁他
- What's going on here?
-Nothing.
这里发生了甚么事?没事
在看“如何读书”甚么的结果大家都兴奋起来了
Just "Reading is Fundamental" shit.
We got all excited.
Clear outta here. Now.
全出去 现在
没问题  全都走
- No problem.
-All of you.
I think we settled the fish thing.
我想买鱼的事定了 史努比
The fish. Yeah.
这鱼 喔!对不起……
That's how you do the shake, partner.
这是我们握手的方法，老弟
Paper says there's ten grand each on you,
Chino and Lulu.
报上说你们各悬赏一万  —奇诺和陆露
They say anything about Karen?
他们有没有提到凯伦
只说她跑了
Just that she got away. Here.
杰克
没关系
-(MAN YELLS)
-That's all right. It's in the pool.
有没有说她和葛兰走了以後怎样?
Did it say what happened after
she left with Glenn?
I don't know. You'll have to ask Glenn.
你得问葛兰
He's probably on his way to Detroit,
which is where we should be.
他可能正在去底特律的路上 我们也该去
你知道你在干么吗?
Do you realize what you're doing?
Worrying about a woman who works for
law enforcement?
这女人是执法人员
You wanna have cocktails
with a woman who tried to shoot you.
你想和对你开枪的女人喝鸡尾酒?
- Do you hear what I'm saying?
-Do you think this old guy's her boyfriend?
你在听吗?你想这老家伙是她男朋友?
It's the only photo she has.
只有这张相片
Am I going to Detroit by myself?
我一个人去底特律?
The longer we stay here,
the better the chance
待在这儿越久，就越可能……
that either Glenn screws up,
葛兰可能搞砸
or we get busted, or both.
也可能我们被捕，或两个都是
这是弗理?
MARS HALL: This is Foley?
凯伦?
这是弗理?
This is Foley?
一点也不像……
He doesn't even look like that.
- No?
-Mmm-mmm. He looks a lot like...
不像?他看起来比较像……
不一样
Different.
Wyatt Earp is here.
怀特尔普来了
嗨  嗨
感觉怎样?好一点了吗?
还好
- How you feeling? Better?
-Good.
你父亲照顾你?他请假一礼拜…
- Your dad taking care of you?
-He took the week off
to take care of me and all he's done
is work on his boat.
想照顾我，但他却只在修他的船
This is Ray Nicolet.
这是雷尼可
嗨
- I heard a lot about you.
-Likewise.
我听了好多关于你的事  彼此彼此
Ray's working with the F.B.l.
task force on the prison break.
雷正与调查局特勤小组一同调查越狱案
告诉我，雷，你有没有穿过“便衣”字样的衣服?
Tell me, Ray, do you ever
wear one that says "Undercover"?
- No.
-How's it going?
没有  事情进展如何?
Sit down.
坐下来
不错 我们捉到其中一个
Good. We caught one of them.
是弗理吗?从线民的线索来的
- Was it Foley?
-Was it off a tip?
有人在机场附近看到他们俩个
Somebody spotted two of them
near the airport.
打了报案电话
Called in the number.
- The reward did it.
-Was it Foley?
是悬赏起了作用是弗理吗?
RAY: No, Linares, one of the Cubans.
不是，是里纳兹，古巴帮中的一个
We went in with full SWAT,
two choppers, the whole deal.
我们与霹雳小组，两架直升机一起攻进去，
里纳兹开始开枪，所以我们先逮他
Linares goes nuts,
starts shooting, so we took him out.
奇诺溜了
Chirino got away.
- Foley hadn't been there?
-RAY: No, strictly Cubans.
弗理不在现场  只有古巴人而已
弗理搭了车，他一定另有计划
Foley had a ride.
He must have his own agenda.
He seems to be the only guy
who knows what he's doing.
他好像是唯一知道自己在干什么的人
(PHONE RINGING)
对不起
喂？
Yeah, she is. Just a minute, please.
她在，请等一下
凯伦
喂？嗨!
你知道我是谁吗?
You know who this is?
Yes. (WHISPERING) Five minutes.
知道 五分钟
那么，雷
- So, Ray.
-Yeah.
有些事我感到奇怪
There's something I'm wondering.
The headline reads, "I Slept With
a Murderer, Says Shaken Miami Woman."
报纸标题说有个迈阿密女人说她同杀人犯睡觉
- JACK: Who answered the phone?
- None of your business.
谁接的电话  与你无关
可能对你来说我还不够成熟
Maybe I'm not old enough for you.
那是我父亲  真的?
- It was my dad.
- Really?
他一脸警察相  你怎么会知道?
- He's got a cop's face.
-How do you know?
你拿了我的皮夹  还有你的枪
- You have my wallet.
-And your gun.
- Think I can have 'em back?
-How do we do that?
我可以拿回来吗?要怎么做?
Stop by my dad's place and drop 'em off.
来我父亲家，丢在他那里
I'll give them to the SWAT guy
who answers the door.
我干脆给应门的霹雳小组特警算了
There's a guy here
on the task force right now.
现在有个特勤小组的家伙在这里
Maybe I should put him on the phone.
也许我该让他讲
- You wouldn't do that.
-Why not?
你不会这样做  为什么不？
You're having too much fun.
你玩得很愉快嘛
She fixes him pork chops and rice.
她替他煮了猪排饭
Next thing you know,
they're making love on the sofa.
接著，他们就在沙发上做爱
She says he was very gentle.
她说他很温柔
Chirino shows up at the
house, says he misses his little girl.
奇里诺来了，说他想他的小女人
She feels sorry for him.
Next thing you know, boom!
她觉得对不起他 接著…砰
- On the couch.
-That's how you score now?
在沙发上  这就是你们目前的进展?
是吧
I guess.
There's something I've been wondering.
我一直在想些事
Whatever happened to your uncle Cully?
你的卡利叔呢?
Think he's gonna tell you where I am?
希望他告诉你我在哪?
- Unless you want to.
- He's dead.
除非你要  他死了
Did 27 years before he got out,
坐了27年车
and he died a few years later
in a charity hospital
出狱几年后，死在慈善医院
making up for all the good times
he missed.
弥补所有他错过的好时光
我绝不会那么做
That's not gonna be me.
One last score, retire to some island?
Is that the idea?
最后一搏，退休到某小岛?是嘛?
杰克  我本身偏爱山区
I'm partial to mountains myself,
不过你喜欢小岛，我们就去小岛
but if you like islands,
we'll make it an island.
“我们”是指?我和你可以…
- What do you mean, "we"?
-You and I can make it...
- You better see this.
-Is that Buddy?
你最好来看看  那是巴蒂吗?
What? No. Okay. Bye-bye.
什么?好 拜拜
So she's a married woman.
所以，她已婚了  正确
But she goes to bed with a prison escapee
because
她和逃犯上床，因为……
he tells her that he misses his little girl.
他说他想念他的小女人
She tells the world about it.
But you protect her.
她告诉全世界的人，但你却保护她
You don't reveal her name.
你没泄漏她的姓名
That makes it sound like
what she was doing was okay
听起来她做得不错
as long as her husband doesn't find out.
只要她老公没发现
就像偷腥的家伙说老婆不知情就不受伤
Like a guy who cheats on his wife. Says
what she doesn't know won't hurt her.
- Dad.
-What?
爸  干嘛？
Ray, I wanna show you
something in the living room.
雷，让你看个东西 在客厅里
很高兴跟你聊天
Good talking to you.
我也是
You too.
NEWSCASTER: Federal law enforcement
agents raided a squatters camp
今天早上，联邦警察临检一个在迈阿密
north of Miami International
Airport this morning
国际机场北边的流浪汉聚所
looking for fugitives from Tuesday's
escape from Glades Prison.
搜寻周二从葛雷兹监狱脱逃的逃犯
F.B.l. officials confirm that one of
the escapees, Aurelio Linares,
其中一名，奥里李纳兹
-was killed...
- JACK: Chino will want to talk to me.
被杀死  奇诺会找我
Chino's runnin' for his life.
He don't give a shit about you.
奇诺忙著逃命，根本不甩你
He'll know I gave him up.
He's gonna wanna find me.
他会知道我放弃他了 他会要找我
Maybe see Adele, see what she knows.
也许问阿黛儿 看她知道什么?
He knows where she lives?
他知道她住哪?
杰克！
We were talking once, drinking rum,
我们曾一起聊天喝过酒
and I may have mentioned Adele.
我可能提过她
How she worked for a magician.
He got all interested.
她曾替魔术师工作过 他很感兴趣
He said, "How do you saw
the woman in half?"
他说，“你怎么把女人锯成两半？”
He wanted to meet her,
see her if she came to visit.
当她来探监时，他想见见她
So you call her up.
Tell her don't talk to any Cubans.
所以你打了电话 要她不要跟古巴帮讲话
电话可能被监听了  没错
- The phone's probably tapped.
-You're right.
Which means they have her place
staked out.
就是说她被监视了
Shit!
该死
(PHONE RINGING)
阿黛儿 德利西
Adele Delisi speaking.
是阿黛儿吗?是啊!
- CHINO: This is Adele?
- Yes, it is.
抱歉  打错了
Sorry. Wrong number.
Nice disguise.
乔装得不错
我是个观光客
I'm a tourist.
All right, here we go.
你看
Coming up right here on the left.
前面这里左手边
- The guy with the clippers?
-I wonder what the F.B.l.
那个剪树丛的家伙? 我想联邦调查局…
is charging to trim hedges these days?
剪树丛要收多少钱?
- Quite a checker game they got goin'.
-Pull on up.
棋下得有模有样  靠边停
JACK: Oh, man.
噢!天啊
你看得到却得不到
You saw her. That's all you get.
- Let's go to Detroit.
-Now you're talkin', brother.
我们去底特律吧  你总算说了句人话
ADELE: I'll say one thing for Jack,
he's very considerate.
我得替杰克说句话，他很体贴
- Lights on or off, you know?
-Really?
嗯，时好时坏的
是啊
Adele, listen.
阿黛儿，听著
I just want to find him before he does
something else and makes it worse.
我只是想在事情搞得更糟前找到他
巴蒂会照顾他
Buddy'll take care of him.
Keep him out of trouble.
He's Jack's conscience.
不让他惹麻烦 他是杰克的良知
他们大概一起抢过50家银行
They must have robbed fifty banks
together.
- They were a really great team.
-Until they got busted.
是最佳拍档  直到他们被抓
那不是杰克的错，那是因为……
That wasn't Jack's fault.
That was on account of
Buddy. He decided to call
his sister and confess to the job
巴蒂 他决定在他们行动之前
before they'd done it instead of after.
向他姊姊坦白
She called the F.B.l. They both
ended up at Lompoc.
她打给联邦调查局 结果两个都进了兰坡
I think Buddy felt kind of bad about that.
我想巴蒂有点愧疚
Do you have any idea
where I could find Buddy?
阿黛儿，你知道在哪儿可找到巴蒂?
或葛兰?
Or Glenn?
(KNOCKING)
CHINO: Mira, Adele, you in there?
米拉，阿黛儿，在吗?
- Yes.
-CHINO: Mira, I'd like to speak to you.
在  米拉，我想和你谈谈
你是谁?伊米 你以前的老板
- Who is it?
-Emile, the guy you used to work for?
给我你的电话和地址
He gave me your number
and where you live.
米拉 我在找助理 我能和你谈谈吗?
I'm looking for an assistant.
Can I speak to you?
好
You did work for Emile?
你替伊米工作过?
I was Emile's box jumper for four years.
我当过伊米四年的盒装美人
你是什么?他的盒子?
You were what? His box?
His assistant.
他的助理
You say you perform in the Miami area?
你说你在迈阿密表演?
CHINO: Here, there, you know.
到处都去
I was a magician in Cuba. They used
to call me Manuelito the Magician.
我在古巴是魔术师 他们都叫我“蛮牛”魔术师
Mira, can you open'?
米拉，开个门
- I'm not dressed.
-I'm a good friend of Jack Foley.
我没穿衣服  我是杰克弗理的好友
- CHINO: You know Jack?
-Who are you?
你认识杰克?  你是谁?
CHINO: Jose Chirino.
荷西奇里诺
Maybe you heard Jack call me Chino.
I'm the same guy.
也许你听过杰克叫我奇诺 我就是
Tell him to wait in the hall.
You have to get dressed.
叫他等等：你要穿衣服
Wait in the hall. You have to get dressed.
在外面等 你要穿衣服
Tell me where to find Jack
and I don't bother you no more.
告诉我哪里找得到杰克，我就不再烦你
好啦！拜托
Come on, please!
- I don't know where he is.
-I helped Jack escape.
我不知道他在哪  我帮过杰克逃狱
- CHINO: Open this fucking door...
-I'm gonna call the police.
米拉, 打开这该死的门……我要叫警察了
CHINO: Why you gonna do that
to a friend of Jack?
为什么要那样对杰克的朋友?
够了
That's it!
(CHINO GROANING)
米拉 拜托！
- Adele!
-Give me your hand.
阿黛尔！阿黛尔！手给我
你不是阿黛尔  联邦警察，你被拘捕了
- You not Adele!
-I'm a U.S. marshal and you're under arrest.
Get my bag, Adele.
把皮包给我，阿黛儿
I think there's a misunderstanding.
我想这有些误会
好皮包
You got nice bag.
Let's say we just forget about it.
I go home...
这件事就算了吧 我回家……
- Shut up.
-Who the hell taught you how to do that?
闭嘴！谁该死地教你那样做?
- Give me your other hand.
-Okay.
另一只手给我
好
(CHINO GROANS)
我得去小便
I gotta go make pee-pee.
你好过份
You are mean!
我要找律师 你侵犯我的人权
I'm gonna call my lawyer.
This is human rights violation.
丹尼尔伯波顿  凯伦西思柯
Daniel Burdon, please. Karen Sisco.
米拉, 阿黛儿  可以问个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
记得你表演的那个魔术吗?
You know that trick you do?
Karen? Where are you?
I've been trying to reach you.
凯伦?你在哪?我一直在找你
When you're in the box
and they saw you in half?
他们把你锯成一半时
- I'm at Adele Delisi's.
-it's magic.
我在阿黛儿德利西家  是魔术呀
We already talked to her.
That's a dead end.
我们已经找过她啦  死巷一条
如果我带奇里诺回去，你会让我加入特勤小组?
If I bring in Chirino,
will you put me on the task force?
- DANIEL: Sure.
-They put the saw through, and separate it.
当然  他们插入锯子，再分开盒子
不过你怎么动脚趾头?
But how do you twinkle your toes?
You bring Chirino in,
and you can be on the task force.
如果你带奇里诺回来，就可以加入特勤小组
That's all I wanted to know.
这就是我想知道的  好
别管那个前妻了
Now, forget about the ex-wife,
and get over to the Adams Hotel?
回亚当斯旅馆去
知道了
You got it.
不！
No!
就这样而已  是假脚
- That's it.
-Fake legs.
假脚? 那你怎么……
Fake legs? How you gonna...
谢啦, 阿黛儿
Thanks, Adele.
CHINO: How do they twinkle their toes,
if it's fake?
如果是假脚，怎么能动呢?
亚当斯旅馆
First thing we do in Detroit, we find Glenn,
我们到底特律第一件事就是找葛兰
and we find a window to throw him out of.
然后把他扔出窗去
I was thinkin', if I was Glenn
我想，如果我是葛兰……
taking down the Ripper, where would I go?
动了瑞利的脑筋，会去哪里
Except if you were Glenn,
you wouldn't be thinkin'.
但如果你是葛兰，就根本不会动脑筋
Remember Snoopy Miller,
his pal from the joint?
记得史努比米勒，他的好兄弟?
I figured he'd be brain-dead by now.
史努比，我以为他早已死了
Snoop doesn't box anymore.
史努比不再打拳了
Glenn told me that he manages
some fighters at the Kronk.
葛兰说他在克朗克做几个拳击手的经纪人
- Did you get the key?
-They're in Room 613.
拿到钥匙了?  他们在613房
两个人在外面，守著前后门
I want two men outside, front and back.
康诺、杰森，上六楼，掩护走廊两端
Conroy, Jameson, go on up to six.
Cover both ends of the hall.
You're primary. You're secondary.
你先走，你殿后
你把哨
You're point man.
你要用撞门桩吗? 对 干嘛?
- You gonna use a ram?
-Yeah. Why?
The manager's door is metal.
经理的门是铁的
They might all be.
说不定全是
桩打在铁门上制造噪音而已
A ram on a metal door makes
a lot of noise and that's it.
I have a shock lock round on my shotgun.
我的散弹枪里有破锁弹
Fine. Whatever.
好 随便
Two, please.
二楼 谢谢
Two.
你
(CLEARS THROAT)
Let's take the stairs.
走楼梯吧
待在大厅，监视电梯
Take the radio. Stay here
in the lobby and watch the elevator.
丹尼尔，我要上去 你要待在车上也行
- Daniel, I want to go upstairs.
-You can wait in the car if you want to.
You see Foley and Bragg
coming behind us. What do you do?
如果你看到弗理和柏格出现，你会怎么做?
呼叫你吗? 然后让他们上来
- Call and tell you?
-And let them come up.
不要自行逮捕他们 明白吗?
Don't try to make
the bust yourself. You understand?
Is this your floor, ma'am?
是这楼吗，女士?
On! (CHUCKLES) Oh, yes.
噢，是的
It is. I'm sorry. Thank you.
抱歉 谢谢
注意，我们接近目标门口了
Be advised we are approaching the door.
注意，要炸开门了
Be advised we are going to blow the door.
(FIRING)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Going UP?
上楼吗?
I thought I was going up.
我以为是上楼
她一直注视著我
She just looked right at me.
- Who?
-Karen.
谁？凯伦
- Karen Sisco?
-Yeah.
凯伦西斯柯?
She's in the lobby.
她在大厅
她在大厅？对
- She's in the lobby?
-Yeah.
If they know where I live, they know what I
drive. We got to dump this car.
如果他们知道我住哪，就知道我开什么车  我们得弃车
She just sat there, looking right at me.
她就坐在那，看著我
他们不在上面 睁大眼睛
DANIEL: They're not up here.
Keep your eyes open.
Karen, are you there?
凯伦，你在听吗？
MARSHALL: He waved at you?
跟你挥手？
I'm pretty sure he did.
我肯定他有
- Did you wave back?
-I didn't have time.
你也挥手了？来不及了
I imagine you would have, though.
可是我想你会的
Buddy's sister, Regina Mary Bragg,
巴蒂的姊姊，维珍柏格
got two calls from Buddy
in Detroit this morning.
今早接到两通巴蒂从底特律打的电话
她通知波顿
She calls Burdon.
- He got Buddy's address from her, too.
-So?
他还拿到巴蒂的住址  又怎样?
Why does he still
call her after she turned him in?
在她告发他后，为什么还跟她联络?
He doesn't hold a grudge.
他不记恨嘛
But if they have this big score up north,
why did Foley stay in Miami for so long?
如果他们在北方有大计划，为什么弗理待在迈阿密这么久
- Any thoughts on that?
-None I'd like to share.
你觉得呢？我不想说
- I'll call you when I get in.
- Okay.
回来后我再打电话给你  好吧
底特律
真浪费时间
我不单只做买卖和管理拳击手
MAURICE: I don't just deal product
and manage fighters no more.
从上次见面后，很多事都变了
A lot's changed since the last time
you seen me.
I've vertically integrated myself,
you know, diversified.
我把自己变得多元化
I'm into the occasional grand larceny,
我偶尔会偷东西
home invasion, shit like that.
闯空门，做那些鸟事
White Boy Bob here is my all-around man.
白波是我这里的跑腿
My personal bodyguard when I
need one, driver.
需要时，还可以是保镖、司机
Watch the road, White Boy!
Why you lookin' back here?
小心看路啊，白波!干嘛回头?
耶 耶
I like this car, Glenn.
我喜欢这部车，葛兰
你偷了部好车，小子
You stole a good one, boy.
We can roll around in Ripley's
neighborhood
我们可以在瑞利家附近绕……
not get sweated by the private security.
不用怕私人警卫
Ain't gonna have no police on our ass,
nothing like that. It's nice, man.
不会有警察当跟屁虫 不错吧
是!
You still haven't said
how you want to do this thing.
你还没说要怎么干这件事
接到另一个兄弟后，我就一起讲
I'll tell you once
we get one other brother I need.
肯尼，那是墨塞的弟弟……
Kenneth, that's Moselle's brother,
跟白波一道
along with White Boy here.
什么！到了，白波
Here we go, White Boy.
(HONKING)
Who's the fireman?
那个消防员是谁？
Ken Dog.
肯尼那狗小子
- What's up?
-MAURICE: What's happenin', hustler?
嘿?怎么样，大老千?
你怕闻烟味?
This cigarette gonna bother you?
Put that thing out. Ken, this is Glenn.
熄了它 肯尼，这是葛兰
Glenn, that's Kenny,
the dude I was tellin' you about.
葛兰，这是肯尼，我跟你提过的家伙
你就是那个要帮我们打劫有钱白佬的人
You're the one gonna help us
rip off that rich white dude?
- That's him.
-Help you?
就是他  帮你?
Go ahead, White Boy.
开车，白波
等等，看……
Maurice, I am letting you in on this gig,
not...
莫瑞，是我让你加入计划
不是……
You just asked how we gonna do it.
你刚问我们要怎么做
I'm telling you how. We're the experts.
我现在告诉你 我们是专家
The one I'm worried about is you, Glenn.
我担心的是你，葛兰
我？
Me?
Can you step up and actually do this
shit instead of just talking the talk?
你真的可以干这档子事，还是说说而已?
Do what?
干什么？
Walk into a house I picked out.
打劫我挑中的房子
Do this cross-dressing nigger
I used to sell to.
干掉这个以前我和他交易过的黑鬼人妖
- Been dealing on his own.
-What? When?
他自己做买卖  什么事？甚么时候？
Right now.
What you think all this shit is for?
现在 你以为做这档子事是干嘛?
我不用向你证明什么
I don't need to prove shit to you.
The Ripley job is my job.
You're either in or you're not.
瑞利的事是我的事 要不要做随你
You wanna go pop some crack dealer
pissed you off
你想揍惹你生气的毒贩
that is your problem, not mine.
那是你的问题，不是我的
I know you supposed to be cool
我知道你酷
but you ain't got to give me
no tone of voice.
但不要用这种口气对我说话
If you don't like what I'm sayin', bounce
off this whip anytime.
你不高兴我说的随时可以走
我想我们都忘了这是我的事
I think we're forgetting
that this is my whip.
(LAUGHING)
我提起的
I brought it up.
听著 我说这是我的车，就是我的
Come on, man. If I say
this is my car, you know this is my car.
You just get yourself another one.
你自己去找另一部
If I say we in on this Ripley shit, we
in on it, with or without you.
不管你要不要，我们都决定进行
If I say you do this motherfucker
如果我要你干掉这个混蛋
to show me you got balls,
来证明你有种
guess what else you gonna do?
你猜你该怎么做?
到了
WHITE BOY: We're here.
Tighten up your panties, boy.
绑紧裤子，小子
Hacksaw. I'll take that.
铁锯 我来拿
斧头
Hatchet.
拿斧头干嘛
What are you gonna do with a hatchet?
去好好修理那混蛋
Let's get some fire to that ass.
你要．45口径还是手枪?
You want the .45 or the Glock?
葛兰？
(GUN FIRING)
狗屎，小子
Worse than you thought
it was gonna be, right?
比你想得更糟，对吧？
You with the bad boys now.
现在你跟坏人一夥了
走吧
Let's go.
BUDDY: What do you think?
你认为怎么样？
I think Glenn opened his big mouth and
now we got another partner.
我想葛兰很惊奇，我们有了另一个兄弟
Hey, Studs, how ya doin'?
想加入
你们在这干嘛?
What are you guys doin' here?
Weren't you expecting us?
你在等我们吗?
Somebody finally step on your sunglasses?
终于有人踩了你的墨镜
- I don't know.
-Whose blood you got on your shirt?
我不知道  你的衬衫上是谁的血?
These guys are crazy.
那些家伙疯了
史努比 那些家伙疯了
- Snoop!
-Shit.
我们有麻烦？
We have a problem here?
Jack Foley, famous bank robber.
杰克弗理，有名的银行大盗
史努比米勒，有名的拳手经纪人
Snoopy Miller, famous fight thrower.
I read you broke out of a prison
down in Florida.
报上说你从佛罗里达逃狱
是那样的？那里全是低级的人，史努比
Low class of people there, Snoop.
再叫一次，你头会撞壁
Call him that again,
I'll put your head through a wall.
What? You mean "Snoop"?
什么? 你说“史努比?”
白波是说没人叫我史努比了
Nobody calls me Snoopy
anymore is what White Boy Bob means.
他只是有点粗鲁 你懂嘛?
He's just a little crude with it.
You know what I mean?
我全抛脑后了，伙伴
I left all that behind me, partner.
你叫这白痴“白波?”
But you call this bozo "White Boy."
白波曾是个拳手
White Boy Bob used to be a fighter.
你现在做甚么，白波?
What do you do now, White Boy Bob,
除了射掉你的大嘴巴?
outside of shoot your big mouth off?
像在监狱大院一样  就这样
- Like being back in the yard.
-Just like it.
Nobody backing down or nothing.
不准退出
You back down, you just a pussy.
谁要退出，谁就是胆小鬼
为什么你们全在底特律?葛兰没告诉你?
- Why y'all in Detroit anyway?
-Glenn didn't tell you?
葛兰?什么?我以为你们被抓了
- Glenn? What?
-I thought you guys were busted.
为什么?因为你留我们站在路旁
Why? 'Cause you left us
standing on the side of the road?
Oops.
噢
Look, Snoop, I don't know
what Glenn promised you,
听著，我不知道葛兰答应了什么
现在计划是
but here's the deal.
Buddy and I get half
of anything we get off of Ripley.
从瑞利那里得到的钱我和巴蒂拿一半
Anything else, you guys can cut up any
way you want.
其他的，你们去分
为什么不到外面谈?
Why don't we talk about this outside?
- Nice in here. It's warm.
-MAURICE: It's like 90 degrees in here.
这里舒服 很温暖 这里大概90度
有时有100度以上
Sometimes it's 100 up in this mug.
That's the way Emmanuel like to keep it.
因为伊曼喜欢保持这样
Keep his fighters mean and lean like
Tommy Hearns.
把他的拳手养得瘦瘦凶凶的像汤米贺恩一样
我要去个地方
I got someplace to be.
星期五晚上来看比赛
Come to the fights Friday night.
We'll sit down,
chop it up, you know, look it over.
我们坐下来，慢慢谈 讨论一下计划
州立剧院  到时见
- State Theater.
-We'll see you then.
RIPLEY: It must take a lot of balls to walk
into a bank and stick it up with a gun.
拿枪打劫银行一定要很大的勇气
I don't know. I never used
a gun before in my life.
我不知道 我从没用过枪
You're kidding.
你开玩笑
You'd be surprised what you can get
if you ask the right way.
如果你做得巧妙，你会得到意想不到的东西
就因为你，我不敢把钱存在银行
You're the reason
I don't keep my money in the bank.
So where do you keep your money?
那你放在哪里?
Talking about all those uncut diamonds.
我是说那些没加工过的钻石
- I know what you're talking about.
-You're the one with balls.
我知道你在说什么 你有胆量
跟葛兰说过吗?
Say something like that to Glenn?
Come on, nobody's going to believe Glenn.
得了，谁会相信葛兰
- Do you believe Glenn?
-No, I don't.
你相信他吗?我不
就算是真的，他也要知道我藏在哪里
Even if it was true, he'd still have to know
where I keep 'em.
你跟他说藏在你家
You told him you keep 'em in your house.
It's a very big house.
How much longer you in here for?
我家很大 你要在这儿待多久?
22个月，三天，两个钟头
22 months, three days, two hours.
为什么?因为我可以雇像你这样的人
- Why?
-'Cause I could use a guy like you.
一个知道怎么才能做得巧妙的人
Somebody that knows how to ask
for things in the right way.
我是说在你出狱后
I'm talking about when you're out of here.
你不可能老打劫银行，对不对?
You can't rob banks forever, can you?
我可不是一个上班族  谁是?
- I'm not exactly a nine to five type.
-Who is?
我以为人人都喜欢艾迪
I thought everybody liked Eddie.
你好吗，雷? 我冷死了
- How you doin', Ray?
-I'm freezing.
But I'm getting warmer.
我可是开始暖和起来了
除了上次我们合作很愉快以外
Other than we had so much fun
the last time we worked together,
why come to me instead of the F.B.l.?
为什么找我，不找联邦调查局
All the F.B.l. will do
is send me to get coffee.
调查局只会叫我去买咖啡
你知道吗?你是对的
You know what? You're right.
去年缉毒局想要抓葛兰说他持有毒品
Last year, DEA had a Glenn Michaels
on possession with intent.
但没有成功  开车
- They couldn't make it stick.
-Move this car.
In his statement he said he was
coming to Detroit to see a friend
葛兰说他要来底特律看朋友
谈有关工作的事
about job opportunities.
- Who was the friend?
-Maurice Miller,
什么朋友 莫瑞米勒，
also known as Snoopy,
used to be a prizefighter.
浑名叫史努比，以前是拳手
I know Snoopy. He's a whack job.
我知道史努比，这人很难搞
Thinks he's Sugar Ray Leonard.
Hangs out on the west side
在西部
和另外几个头号笨蛋一起
with a couple of other first-rate nut cases.
- I need a last-known address.
-27-10 coming in.
我要地址  2710
- You need a what?
-A last known address.
你要什么?  最近的地址
That your car?
那是你的车吗?
No way. I don't want you talking to Miller
alone.
我不喜欢你和米勒单独见面
得了，雷，我是联邦人员，我有枪
Come on, Ray. I'm a federal officer.
I can handle myself. I'm armed.
明天我再打电话告诉你地址
I'll call you tomorrow with the address.
Thank you, Raymond.
谢谢你，雷
你看报纸了吗?
BUDDY: You see the paper?
她很上镜头  除了这
- JACK: It's a terrific shot of her.
- BUDDY: Outside of that.
我不认为她来此跟我们有关系
I don't think her being here
has anything to do with us.
她是来渡假，因为这里狗屎天气
She came here on vacation because
she likes shitty weather.
我想她是来抓葛兰的
I think she's after Glenn.
那女的在吗
The girl still there?
BUDDY". They don't stay the whole night
unless you pay for it.
除非你给钱，否则她们不会留下过夜
你有没有告诉你姐姐?有，我刚打了 她为我祈祷
- Did you tell your sister?
-Yeah, I just hung up. She prayed for me.
- How long were you on the phone?
- Two hours.
你打了多久?两个小时
- How long were you with the girl?
-45 minutes.
你跟那女的呢?四十五分钟
你跟你姐姐谈到瑞利了吗?
You didn't tell your sister about Ripley,
did you?
别再提我姐姐了
Just forget about my sister.
If Karen Sisco is tailing Glenn,
we're fucked.
如果凯伦盯著葛兰，我们就惨了
Tomorrow night at the fights we all get
picked up.
明晚我们都会被抓
Let's drive by where we're meeting
tonight, check it out
我们先去剧院，看看
再去瑞利家
-and go by Ripley's too, while we're at it.
-Yeah, all right.
好吧
安瑟旅馆，我能否为你服务?请找凯伦西思柯
FEMALE OPERATOR: Athenaeum Hotel,
how may I help you?
Karen Sisco, please.
- OPERATOR: Hello. Best Western.
- Karen Sisco, please.
好西部旅馆  请找凯伦西思柯
莫塞米勒吗?你找谁?
- Moselle Miller?
-What do you want?
我找莫瑞  你找到他，说他那只狗死了
- I'm looking for Maurice.
-You find him, tell him the dog died,
and I'm out of grocery money.
我没有伙食钱了
- KENNETH: Who you talkin' to?
-Lady lookin' for Maurice.
你在和谁说话?有个女的找莫瑞
她要什么  她没说
KENNETH: What does she want?
MOSELLE: Hasn't said.
那不是莫瑞?那是我弟弟肯尼
- That's not Maurice?
-That's Kenneth, my brother.
- KENNETH: Ask her what she want with him!
-You ask her!
问她找他干什么 你去问她!
- Maurice business is none of my business.
-KENNETH: You damn right.
莫瑞的事与我无关 你妈的对
State Theater? Who's fightin'?
剧场? 谁在比赛?
Nigger, what?
黑鬼，怎么样?
(KENNETH LAUGHING)
KAREN: I'm looking for somebody
I think Maurice knows.
我在找一个莫瑞认识的人
You're not with probation, one of those?
你不是缓刑小组来的吧?
不是  你是律师吗?
- No.
-You a lawyer?
不是 我在找葛兰麦克
No. I'm looking
for somebody named Glenn Michaels.
Glenn? I don't know any Glenn.
我不认识什么葛兰
He said he stayed here last November.
他说他去年11月待在这里
- Here in this house?
-He said he stayed with Maurice.
在这房子里?  他说他和莫瑞在一块
连莫瑞都不常来了
He ain't even here that much.
I'd like to know where he goes,
but at the same time
我想知道他到那去了
又不想知道，你懂吗?
I don't wanna know, you understand?
我懂
- You say your dog was killed?
-Got run over by a car.
你的狗死了?被车碾死的了
它叫什么?它是母的，叫塔菲
- What'd you call him?
-it was a she. Named Tuffy.
你想我在那里可以找到莫瑞?
Where do you think I might find Maurice?
我不知道 健身房?拳击场?
I don't know. The gym, the fights.
他从不错过拳赛 明天晚上剧场里有拳赛
He don't miss the fights. There are some
tomorrow night at the State Theater.
他以前都带我去  剧场
- He used to take me.
-The State Theater.
Why you askin' all these questions
about Maurice?
你为什么问一大堆有关莫瑞的事?
She lookin' for a man named Glenn.
她在找一个叫葛兰的人
Did I ask you?
Go on and do something with yourself.
我问你了吗?办你的事去
你去给我们拿点吃的来
Why don't you take your ass
and get us some shrimp.
- You're a fighter.
-How you know that?
你打拳
你怎么知道？
- I can tell.
-I was.
我看得出来
我是
'Til I got my retina detached two times.
直到我的视网膜剥落了二次
- What'd you fight, about middleweight?
-Light.
你打那一级?中量级?轻量级
Super middleweight,
once my body developed.
超中量级，等我长壮一点
- What you go about, what, a bantam?
-Flyweight.
你打那一级?羽量级?蝇量级
黑鬼，怎样?该知道你的等级
Nigger, what? You know your divisions.
Do you like the fights?
You like the rough stuff?
你喜欢打拳吗?你喜欢动粗吗?
我想你一定喜欢
I bet you do.
You like to get down and tussle a little bit?
想不想下来干一场?
Like me and Tuffy, before she got run over.
像从前我和塔菲一样
We'd get down on the floor and tussle
all the time.
我们常在地上扭在一块
我告诉它“塔菲”，你这只好狗这个好吃的给你”
I'd say to her, "You a good bitch,
Tuffy. Here's a treat for ya."
我给塔菲所有母狗都爱的，你知道是什么吗?
I'd give Tuffy what all good bitches
love best, and you know what that is?
Know what that is? A bone.
知道那是什么吗?一块骨头
I'll give you a good bone too, girl.
我也会给你一块好的骨头
You're not my type.
你不是我喜欢的那种人
That shit don't mean nothin' to me.
那话对我没意义
- I let the monster out, you do what it wants.
-I gotta go.
我掏出我的大家伙……我得走了
- Maybe we'll see each other again.
-No, we gonna tussle first.
说不定我们会再见面  不，我们先干一场
Damn it! What the fuck was that?
妈的!那是什么鬼东西?
You wanted to tussle. We tussled.
你想干一场 我们来干
那是个大房子
BUDDY: That's a big ass house.
JACK: Place almost looks like a prison.
这地方就像监狱
BUDDY: No doubt he's got some
serious security system.
他可真有一套，复杂的保安系统
Time comes, we knock on the door,
see if he wants to discuss old times.
到时候，我们去敲门看他要不要叙旧
太简单了  酷
- The easy way.
-Cool.
Think he'll let us in with Snoop
and that musclebound asshole?
有史努比和那一身肉的混蛋他会让我们进去吗?
Nobody's gonna be with us.
没有别人
We go to the fights tomorrow
night, hear Snoopy's big plan,
明晚我们去看拳赛听听史努比的大计划
then we go in ahead of him. Alone.
然后我们比他快一步
I can dig it.
好主意
Glenn deals with the Snoop,
while we off livin' the good life.
当我们去逍遥的时候让葛兰去应付史努
You know anybody
who's done one last big score
你知道有谁做了一大笔
and then gone on to live the good life?
然後就逍遥法外了?
There's a chance
we'll walk out of here with nothin'.
我们也有可能空手而归
I say, let fate decide.
我看，听天由命吧
Fate? Who are you,
the fuckin' Dalai Lama now?
命运?你是什么，他妈的达赖喇嘛?
It's my sister.
是我姊姊
My sister believes in fate but not hell.
我姊姊相信命运不相信地狱
That's why she stopped praying for all the
lost souls,
她不再为丧失灵魂的人祷告
since you don't hear
about Purgatory anymore.
虽然你不肯再听赎罪之类的话
But every day,
she prays that Buddy don't fuck up.
但她每天仍为巴蒂祷告希望他不出事
你认为呢?
What do you think?
你认为地狱存在吗?
Do you think there's a hell?
It's called the Glades Correctional Institute.
葛雷兹监狱就是
I'm not going back there,
or any place like it.
我决不回到像那样的地方去
他们用枪对著你，你就得去
They put a gun on you, you'll go, brother.
They put a gun on you,
you still have a choice.
那怕有枪，你还是有选择的余地
所以，弗理先生
MAN: So, Mr. Foley.
Mr. Ripley and I have had a long talk
about your role in the company.
瑞利先生和我长谈过你在公司上班的事
He felt you'd be happiest
working here in Miami.
他觉得你在迈阿密上班会愉快些
- How's that sound to you?
-Great.
怎么样？好极了
Good. You're about a 42 long, right?
好 你穿42号加长的，对吗?
I'm about a 42.
我大概是穿42号
Like, 42 regular.
像，42号普通的
- Let's see how she fits.
-What is that?
穿穿看合不合身  这是什么?
Your uniform.
你的制服
My uniform.
我的制服?
弗理先生 弗理先生
Sir. Excuse me, sir.
先生! 请等等
- You can't go in there!
-A security guard?
你不能进去!有警卫？
- What are you, stoned?
-Hey. Take it easy!
你搞什么，昏了头啦? 嘿，别发火!
It's all right, Peggy. It's under control.
没关系，佩姬 没事了
听我说
I wasn't sure that you'd show up here,
but I was sure if you did,
我不确定你会来 但我知道如果你来了
you'd throw this job in my face.
你也会把这差事扔到我脸上
让我告诉你吧
Let me tell you something.
Every single thing you've done
with your life up to this point
到今天为止你所做的
in the real world means nothing.
都没有任何意义
Less than nothing.
一点意义也没有
You're a bank robber.
你是个抢银行的
That's not a very marketable skill.
那是个见不得人的本事
We don't see a lot of old bank robbers
walking around
谁看过抢银行的
with a pension plan, now do we?
领养老金了?
I think you know this.
That's why you're here.
我想你懂这个道理所以你才会来这里
今天，我给你……
Today, I've offered you
a lousy job with a lousy wage.
一个烂工作，烂薪水
You want something better?
Show me you can change.
你要好一点的工作?证明你能改头换面给我看
我才会给你好点的差事
Then I'll offer you something better.
A lot better.
在这之前，老兄，你得去赚
Until then, my friend, you'll have to earn it.
How, Dick? The way you earn it?
怎么赚，狄克?像你这样?
Married some rich broad
owns the company,
讨个开公司的富婆
selling it, then divorcing her?
卖了公司，再和她离婚?
What's this "pull yourself up by
the bootstraps" bullshit?
说什么“自食其力”的狗屎?
Back in prison, a guy like you
in a place like that?
在监狱里，像你这种人?
You were ice cream for freaks.
A goddamned dumpling.
一定会被整得稀巴烂
Maurice and a dozen other guys would
have bled you till you had nothing.
莫瑞和其他的家伙会要你的命
Until you were nothing. I saved your ass!
打死你 是我救了你的狗命
So pardon me if I won't sit on a stool,
抱歉我不愿坐椅子上
and say, "Sign in here, please,"
or "You can't park here."
还要说“请签名”或“你不能停在这里”
我不能干这种事，狄克
I can't fuckin' do it, Dick!
I'm disappointed in you.
你让我失望
又来了 他答应了你们这些人什么?
Here we go.
What job did he promise you boys?
- There's two ways we can do this.
-What are they?
我们有二种办法  什么办法?
山托斯银行
I gotta get a better pair
of shoes and some things for tomorrow.
我必需买双好鞋以及明天用的东西
我们一会儿见
- Let's hook up later.
-Yeah, okay.
好
I better go call my sister.
我最好打个电话给我姊姊
WAITRESS: Can I get you anything?
要喝点什么？
I'll have a bourbon. Water back.
我要波本和水
好
Why don't you do us again?
你为什么不问我们还要什么?
Celeste, put the lady's drink on our bill.
席莱，那女士的酒算我们的
- They want to buy your drink for you.
-I get that.
他们要请你喝杯酒  我想也是
- Tell them I'd rather pay for my own.
-Okay.
告诉他们我情愿自己付
好的
I'll find out.
我来问问看
对不起
Excuse me.
My associates and I, we made a little bet
我和同事们打了个赌
on what you do for a living.
看看你是干哪一行的?
And lwon. Hi, I'm Philip.
我打赢了 我叫菲利普
I'd rather just have a quiet drink and leave.
菲利普，我只想安静的喝一杯酒走
难道你不想知道我是怎么知道的?
Don't you want to know what I guessed?
How I know what you do for a living?
I don't want to be rude.
I just want to be left alone.
我并不想对你不礼貌，我只是想清静一下
她有点冷淡
PHILIP: It's a little cold over there.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I think I know why you're depressed.
我知道你为什么这么沮丧
我能把我的意见告诉你吗?
If I can offer my observation.
I got a hunch you're the new sales rep,
我猜你是新来的推销员
and the client's not exactly knocked out
by the fact that a young lady,
你的客户并不十分满意，因为处理他们户头的
even one as stunning as yourself,
is handling the account.
竟然是一位像你这么年轻的小姐
我猜得很对吧?
Am I close?
我是安迪
I'm Andy.
We're all ad guys. Flew in this morning
from the Apple. New York.
我们都是广告业的，今天早上才从纽约飞来的
Here to pitch Hiram Walker Distillery.
替“河边路人”酒厂做广告
Test market campaign
for the new Margarita mix.
给新的玛格丽特鸡尾酒做试售计划
It's really pretty interesting.
We take this...
那真的是很有意思，比方说
Mex... Hispanic bandito
麦克司…西裔的土匪
with his bullet belts and everything,
and the big Chihuahua hat,
挂著子弹带，拿了家伙戴了一个大帽子
然后他拔出六发子弹的枪
and he pulls out his six-guns.
- These guys back here...
-Andy.
我背后的那些家伙  安迪
Really. Who gives a shit?
谁管这些狗屎?
要不要告诉我怎么回事儿?滚开，安迪
- Do you want to tell me what happened?
-Beat it, Andy.
安迪
PHILIP: What'd you do?
你做了什么?
(LIGHTER CLICKS)
- Can I buy you a drink?
-Yeah, I'd love one.
我能请你喝杯酒吗？好，来一杯
坐下
Sit down.
I'm Gary.
我是盖瑞
I'm Celeste.
我是席莱
- It takes forever to get a drink here.
-I can go to the bar.
只有一个女侍 我可以到吧台去
- Don't go.
-Are those guys bothering you?
别去 他们烦你了？
They're fine. I mean, you just got here.
没事，你刚到吗?
Here, help yourself.
来，喝一点
- You like bourbon?
-I love it.
你喜欢波本酒?我喜欢
Tell me, Celeste,
what do you do for a living?
席莱，告诉我，你是干哪一行的?
I'm a sales rep, and I came here
to call on a customer,
我是个推销员，来拜访一位客户
but they gave me a hard time
'cause I'm a girl.
因为我是女的，他们就刁难我
Is that how you think of yourself?
你是这么想你自己的吗?
- As a sales rep?
-As a girl.
推销员？女人
- I don't have a problem with it.
-I like your hair.
我无所谓  我喜欢你的发型
- I like your outfit.
-This is my second favorite outfit.
我喜欢你的打扮  这是我第二喜欢的一套衣服
I had a first favorite,
but it got ruined, and I had to get rid of it.
我最喜欢的一套已经被糟蹋了只好扔了
- You did?
-it smelled.
真的？臭臭的
- Having it cleaned didn't help?
-No.
洗了也没用  对
Gary, what do you do for a living?
盖瑞，你做什么的?
- How far do you want to go with this?
-Don't say anything yet.
你还要这样继续多久?先别说甚么
I don't think it works
if we're somebody else.
没用的，我们就是我们
Gary and Celeste, what do they know?
盖瑞和席莱，他们知道甚么?
- I never played this game before.
-it's not a game.
我没玩过这种游戏  这不是游戏
It's not something you play.
不是你玩的游戏
Does this make any sense to you?
对你有意义吗?
It doesn't have to.
It's something that happens.
不须要有意义，是自然发生的
像在街上第一次看到一个人，你以为你们会擦肩而过，
It's like seeing someone for the first time
like you could be passing on the street,
你们彼此看了几秒……
and you look at each other
and for a few seconds
there's this kind of a recognition...
Like you both know something.
就觉得你们彼此灵犀相通
但下一刻，那人就走了
The next moment, the person's gone,
and it's too late to do anything about it.
也来不及做甚么
You always remember it,
because it was there, and you let it go.
你会永远记得，你错过了某些东西
You think to yourself,
"What if I had stopped?"
你告诉自己，“假如我停下来了呢?”
"What if?"
“假如……”
这种事一生中只会发生几次
And it may only happen
a few times in your life.
- Or once.
-Or once.
或一次  或一次
你怎么找到我的?
How'd you find me?
啊恩
我在楼下打到你的房间
I called your room from downstairs.
哦
And I if I had answered,
what were you gonna say?
如果我接电话，你要说甚么?
说我是谁，你记得我吗?要不要一起喝一杯？
JACK: Who I was, and do you remember me
me, and want to meet for a drink?
KAREN: If I remembered you?
I came here looking for you.
记得你吗？我来这儿就为找你
然后我会说好 但你知道
I would have
said yes, but for all you know,
I could have had a SWAT team waiting.
Why would you trust me?
我也可能让霹雳小组等著你，你为什么信任我?
JACK: It'd be worth the risk.
值得冒险
KAREN". You like taking risks.
JACK: So do you.
你喜欢冒险  你也是
迟早……
KAREN". You know, sooner or later...
You really wear that suit.
你真的穿那套套装
That's not what you were about to say.
这不是你想说的
Remember how talkative
you were in the trunk?
你记得你在后车厢里多爱讲话?
- Adele said you talk when you're nervous.
-She did, did she?
阿黛儿说你一紧张就爱讲话  她这么说吗?
- You kept touching me, feeling my thigh.
- JACK: But in a nice way.
你一直摸我的大腿  但我没恶意
That SIG you took from me was special.
你拿走的西格枪有特殊意义
My dad gave it to me for my birthday.
是我爸送我的生日礼物
是吗?
你要把我怎么办?
What were you going to do with me?
我还没想出来
JACK: I hadn't really
worked that part out yet.
I just knew I liked you, and didn't want to
我只知道我喜欢你，不想……
leave you and never see you again.
离开你就再也见不到你了
KAREN: Then you waved to me
in that elevator.
你在电梯里招手
JACK: I wasn't sure if you saw that.
我以为你没看到我
KAREN". I couldn't believe it. I had been
我无法相信，我一直…
thinking about you a lot
很想你
and just wondering
what it would be like if we met,
而且一直想如果我们再见面
如果我们能让时间停止
if we could take a time-out.
I was thinking the same thing.
我也这么想
I kept thinking,
"What if we took a time-out?"
如果我们能让时间停止
If we just spent some time together.
如果我们能在一起一段时间
我在街上看到过你  哪里？
JACK: I saw you on the street.
KAREN". Where?
JACK: Outside Adele's.
阿黛儿家外面
KAREN". You went to see her?
JACK". To warn her about Chino.
你去看她?去警告她要小心奇诺
KAREN: So she did help you.
JACK". I don't think we should get into that.
她帮了你?我们不该谈这些
KAREN". You're right.
And I won't ask about Buddy,
对，我也不会问巴蒂的事
或你是否见到了葛兰
or what you guys are doing in Detroit,
or if you've seen Glenn yet...
JACK: Don't talk like that,
because you scare me.
别这么说，你让我害怕
Let's get out of here.
我们走吧
Yeah.
There's something I want you to know.
有些事情我要你知道
I wasn't just looking for a fuck,
if that's what you're thinking.
我并不是在找乐子，如果你是这么想的话
怎么了?
Why are you mad?
Like I was looking for some kinky thrill,
score with the bank robber.
我不是在寻刺激，和一个抢银行的
The way some women go for rough trade.
像有些女人喜欢粗暴的……对
Now I can say that I fucked a U.S. marshal.
Do you think I will?
我不会说我干了一个联邦女警，你想我会吗?
我不知道
I don't know.
Come here.
过来
I know a guy,
我认识一个家伙……
walks into a bank with a bottle,
says it's nitroglycerine.
带了个瓶子进了银行，说那是硝化甘油
He scores some cash off of the teller.
他从柜台搞了些钱
On his way out, he drops the bottle.
it cracks on the floor.
走出银行时，瓶子掉到地上
He slips in it. He smacks up his head.
They get him.
他滑倒跌破了头，被逮了
The nitroglycerine was canola oil.
那油只是沙拉油
I know more fucked-up bank robbers
than ones that know what they're doing.
抢银行的笨贼总比高明的要多
I doubt one in ten knows
what a dye pack is.
我怀疑有几个抢银行的知道什么是染色袋
Most bank robbers are fucking morons.
大部份抢银行的都是蠢蛋
让你到床上找刺激的蠢蛋
For you to go to bed with one
for kinky thrills,
like you were saying,
makes you as dumb as they are.
像你说的，你也变得和他们一样蠢
Now, you are not dumb.
事实上，你不蠢
Why would you think that? Why would you
think that I would think that?
你怎么会那么想?你怎么认为我会那么想?
You're not dumb.
你不蠢
I don't know about that.
我不晓得
You can't do three falls
and think you have much of a brain.
你不能跌了三跤后还认为自己不笨
Come here.
过来
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
You're getting serious on me now.
你现在对我认真了
Tryin' not to.
我尽量不想
I just want to know what's gonna happen.
我只是想知道会发生什么
You know.
你知道的
周五夜拳赛
Put it together now.
Upstairs, not downstairs.
防守 打他上面，下面
- He don't want to see you downstairs!
-You drink like a bitch!
他不想在楼下见到你  你醉得像婊子
Don't go down. Get your tussle on!
别下去，准备打吧
Don't let him out that corner.
别让他离开那个角落
别让他出去
You know what? I gotta go take a pee.
我要去小便
告诉我们干什么?要我们替你扶老二啊
Why tell us?
You want somebody to hold your pecker?
MAURICE: Do that work, Joe!
干下去，乔
Put it together now, Joe!
鼓起精神，乔
对了
That's it, baby!
Take him deep! I love it.
扁他，好极了
Put him to sleep, Joe!
把他打昏，乔  把他打昏，乔
Sit down, Kenny. That's it!
坐下，肯尼，对了
- KAREN: Tryin' to steal this car?
-Don't!
想偷这部车呀  不要!
(PANTING)
I can't believe this!
我不相信
又倒霉了，没一件事情搞对
Another one of those days?
Nothing seems to be going right.
- I don't have the keys.
-I see that.
我没有钥匙  我知道
I mean I am not fucking stealing the car!
我不是要偷这辆车
- You're not?
-No, I already stole it a week ago,
你不是吗?不是，一周前已经偷到手了
whenever it was, in West Palm.
在西棕榈
So I can't be stealing it again, can I?
我不可能再偷一次吧
- Hands on the wheel.
-You're gonna
把手放在方向盘上  你要…
bust me for pickin' up a car?
因为偷车逮捕我?
For the car, for aiding
and abetting a prison escape,
为车，为协助犯人逃狱
and for conspiring to do
whatever you came here for.
还为你到这里搞的不管什么名堂
These guys, they're gonna
be out here any minute looking for me,
那些家伙随时都会出来找我
and they're fucking animals.
他们是禽兽
What's going on, Glenn?
发生什么事，葛兰?
Nothing. I just wanna
get the fuck outta here.
没事，我只是想离开这鬼地方
I thought this whole thing was your idea.
我还以为这件事是你的主意
Ripping off Ripley was my idea,
打劫瑞利家是我的主意
but these guys, they are
in a whole other level of their own.
但这些家伙另有搞法
- Ripley, the Wall Street guy?
-The plan was
瑞利，那个华尔街的家伙?计划是…
to pick him up at his office tomorrow
明天到他办公室接他
and drive him out
to his house in Bloomfield Hills.
搭他到布伦坡他家
现在，我不跟那鸟人做，你知道!
Now I don't give a shit what the guys do.
弗理有份吗?有，但他还没出现
- Foley was part of this?
-Yeah, but he hasn't showed up yet,
-which is good for him.
-Why?
那倒对他好  为什么?
莫瑞要干掉他……
Maurice is gonna kill him
to try to collect the reward money or
something.
想拿赏金甚么的
But you say he hasn't shown up yet.
You think he backed out?
但你说他还没现身，他是打退堂鼓了吗?
I don't know.
He doesn't exactly confide in me.
我不知道，他不会告诉我这些
I wonder why.
奇怪
If you're gonna do this,
let's do it and get out of here.
你如果想做，我们做了就离开这里
我的屁股冻坏了
I am freezing my ass off!
If you wanna get out of here, run.
It'll warm you up.
你想溜，就跑吧，这样会暖和些
(SCOFFS)
哦！哦！
真的？
Really?
I swear to God, if I find out
that you are lying to me...
如果我发现你在骗我，我发誓……
I know, you will find me. I believe it.
我知道，你会找到我的
Hey, you know what I was thinking?
知道我在想什么吗?
If you didn't drive me
to the federal court last summer,
去年夏天如果你没载我到联邦法院
you wouldn't even know who I am.
你就不认识我了
如果我不认识你，葛兰，明天你不是坐牢就是死了
If I didn't know you, Glenn,
by tomorrow you'd be in jail or dead.
Think of it that way. Now run.
要那样去想 现在跑吧
耶! 耶!
(WHISTLING)
I'm tellin' you, the money is here.
我告诉你吧，钱在这里
- Snoop.
-it's the bank robbers.
史努  抢银行的
I'm missin' the fights. Pull up a chair.
我会错过拳赛，抓把椅子来
- Who's sittin' here?
-Glenn.
谁坐在那里  葛兰
But he went to the bathroom a couple
of minutes ago,
他去上厕所了……
-and we ain't seen him since.
-Must've fell in.
之后我们就没见过他  一定是掉到茅坑里了
没错
No doubt.
Sent these two looking for him.
They came back shaking their heads.
叫那两个人去找他，他们没找到
If he left his coat
and he's been gone a while, then...
如果他留下外套，又离开了一阵子……
Car's here, man. I checked.
车还在，我查过了
(BELL DINGS)
我们走了  走了?
- We're leavin'.
-Leavin'?
- What the fuck?
-if Glenn's gone...
干嘛? 如果葛兰跑了…
- Who cares? What does he know?
-I thought everything.
谁在乎，他什么也不知道 我以为他全知道
Glenn know everything
that's supposed to happen tomorrow.
葛兰以为我们明天才要干
He may run and tell somebody that,
but that don't mean shit.
就算他跑了把我们的事告诉别人，也无关紧要
Glenn don't know I changed the plan.
葛兰不知道我改变了计划
It's happenin' tonight.
Soon as we leave here.
今天晚上一离开这里我们就行动
Go back by the house, pick up some shit
we gonna need, and we just gonna do it.
绕到我家，拿些我们需要的家伙，就这么干!
- Give me a minute to talk to Buddy.
-You got two minutes.
给我几分钟跟巴蒂商量  给你两分钟
- Make up your mind.
-I wasn't asking permission.
你作决定  我不是要你批准
- You know they're gonna set us up.
-I get that feeling.
他们会对我们下圈套  我有同感
You think you can get
to the diamonds before they do?
你想我们可以在他们之前找到钻石吗?
I'll make you a deal.
You get outta here right now.
跟你谈个交易，你现在就离开这里
I'll do the job with Snoop, meet
you, give you half.
我和史努一起做，再和你见面分你一半
为什么分我一半?因你帮我逃狱
- Half for doin' what?
-Gettin' me out of Glades, for starters.
Who's gonna watch your back?
谁会在背后照应你?
All right, White Boy. House call.
好了，白鬼，家庭访间
耶, 耶, 耶
(DOORBELL RINGING)
准备好了?好了
- Ready to do this?
-Ready for whatever.
Cool. My shit always work.
正点!我这一套每次都管用
WHITE BOY: Perennial Plumbing.
长生水电
WHITE BOY: Somebody called.
有人打电话给我们
You don't know what you're talking
about, because no one was here.
你搞错了，没人在家
我们去滑雪  耶, 耶, 耶
Let's go skiing.
JACK: You still got time to take me up
on my offer.
你仍可以接受我的条件
BUDDY: And leave you alone
with these assholes?
留你和这些蠢蛋在一起?
- Raymond Cruz.
-It's Karen Sisco. I'm at Ripley's house.
雷门库兹  我是凯伦，我在瑞利家
Maurice Miller and four other
men just forced their way in.
莫瑞米勒和另外四个人刚闯进去
我需要后援
They're armed. I'm gonna need backup.
- Who are you?
-MIDGE: I work here.
你是谁? 我在这里工作
I'm the maid. Fuck off!
我是女佣，别过来
That's exactly what I'm gonna do,
fuck you, then off you.
我偏要这么做，先干你，再扁你
端利在哪里? 他不在这里
- Where Ripley at?
-He isn't here.
- Out for the evening or some shit?
-He's in Florida, Palm Beach.
晚上出去还是搞什么?他在佛罗里达
什么时候回来?你们要等他啊
- When's he due back?
-You gonna wait for him?
瑞利先生整个季节都在那里，从圣诞到复活节
Mr. Ripley's down for the season.
Christmas to Easter.
Stop that shit.
少放屁
You're here all by yourself?
你一个人在这里?
That's right. Just me.
是的，只有我
- Where's Ripley's safe, his valuables?
-I don't have any idea.
瑞利的保险箱和贵重品在哪?我不知道
我谅你也不知道
I fuckin' bet you don't.
We gonna take a look upstairs
in the man's bedroom.
我们要上楼到他的卧室找一找
You and Mr. Buddy look
at all the rooms down here.
你和巴蒂找楼下的房间
Check the paintings, behind the walls.
检查那些画，以及墙后
他一定有保险箱，在这附近
The man's got a safe. It's here somewhere.
What about his place down in Florida?
会不会在他佛罗里达的家里?
If you'd called, we could have checked
the walls down there before we left.
如果你先查明，我们在佛罗里达时，就先查那些墙了
That is, if you'd bothered to find out
where he was.
我是说如果你愿找到他的话
Take this bitch upstairs.
把这婊子带上楼
上楼
You try and trip any alarms,
anything like that,
你如果想按警铃，或甚么的话
you gonna be a dead hazel,
you understand me?
你就死定了，明白吗?
我们在哪里?保险箱在哪里?那里
- Where we at? Where is it?
-Over there.
穿过这个吗?我不滑雪
- Ever wear one of these?
-I don't ski.
Keep an eye on the maid.
I'll have a look around.
看好那个女佣，我要到处看看
Go sit down. Please.
坐下来
Damn, Mo. How's this motherfucker livin'?
妈的，这痞子过这种生活
检查墙上画的后面
Check behind the pictures on the walls.
Hey, Mo. Found some rubbers.
喂，找到一些套子
White Boy, why the fuck
you lookin' under the mattress?
白波，你为什么在床垫下找?
You know dude ain't gonna hide
no diamonds under there.
那家伙不会把钻石藏在那儿的
Damn! Dumb Alabama motherfucker.
妈的，这个痞子
- Where Foley?
-Checkin' the other rooms like you said.
弗理在哪里?照你说的，在检查别的房间
盯好他
Keep an eye on Foley.
(STATIC ON RADIO)
MAURICE: Ken, stop fuckin' with the radio,
put on a CD.
肯，别动那收音机，放张CD
- I don't recognize none of these bands, Mo.
-Just pick somebody.
这些乐队我一个都不认识  随便找一个
What, "How to Sing like Michael Bolton"?
什么，“如何唱的像麦克波顿”
What the fuck you wanna listen to?
你想听什么?
- I like Schubert.
-Schubert? Well, I don't.
我喜欢舒伯特  舒伯特，我不喜欢
弗理!
Foley?
(CLATTERING)
Cool.
酷
911 got you on hold, Richard?
911占线啊，理查
- Foley!
-How you doin'?
弗理!还好吗？
What in God's name is happening here?
到底发生什么事?
- Who's upstairs?
-Snoopy Miller, couple of his friends.
谁在楼上?史努比米勒，几个他的朋友
Maurice, from Lompoc?
莫瑞，兰坡监狱的那个?
Have they got Midge up there?
他们把美姬抓住了吗
What man lets a woman
answer the door this late?
有哪个男人那么晚让女人应门?
We thought it was her husband.
He comes here and checks up on her.
我们以为那是她丈夫来这里查看她
I'm supposed to be down in Florida.
我应该在佛罗里达的
In a few minutes, you'll wish you were.
Let's go. Come on.
待会儿你就会巴不得自己是在佛罗里达了
Sit down. We'll look at your fish.
坐下，看鱼吧
That's workin'. That's workin'.
这个行，这个行
(GASPS)
干你娘，我找到保险箱了
Motherfucker! I found the safe!
Don't go nowhere.
哪儿都别去
妈的，我们要庆祝一下  瞧那婊子
- Shit! We gonna have a party!
-Look at that bitch.
找到保险箱了
They found the safe.
- Fuck.
-Buddy, you remember Richard?
干
巴蒂，你记得理查吗?
嘿，房子不错  谢谢
- Hi. Nice house.
-Thank you.
We just all hit this handle,
我们可以敲这个把手
blow this sucker wide open.
把这炸开
准备一下
Let's get ready.
你想用这玩意儿干掉我
You're gonna kill me with that.
- Where you been, man?
-Found some steaks.
你去哪儿了?找到一些牛排
- Steaks?
-Some big ones, bro.
牛排  好大一块
Come on, blast this damn safe open.
来吧，把这保险箱炸开
他在那儿找吃的  蠢蛋
- He's down there lookin' for food.
-FooL
拿好，不对，到一边去
Hold it. No. Get to the side, man.
On three. One, two, three.
数到三， 一、二、三
- Jesus, they're shooting Midge!
-Sit down, Dick.
老天，他们在对美姬开枪  坐下，迪克
They're trying to open up
the safe, not your maid.
他们在打开保险箱，不是你的女佣
(LAUGHING)
妈的
KENNETH; Shit.
We didn't even crack it.
连个破洞也没有
Hit the hinges.
打那门铰链
Put your finger in your ear, man.
This is gonna be loud.
捂住你的耳朵，这声音会很响
On three. One, two...
数到三，一、二……
The combination is 3-10-44.
暗码是31044
理查的生日  多谢
- Richard's birthday.
-Thank you.
他们挂了?
Are they dead?
我们得找弗理
We gotta find Foley.
Can't believe you're still angry with me
after all this time.
真不敢相信事过境迁你还生我气
I'm not angry with you.
In fact, I'm completely relaxed.
我没生你的气，老实说，我真看开了
I can't figure if it's the fish that are cooling
me out,
我真搞不懂，是鱼让我冷静下来
还是水箱底下那些未切割的钻石
or all those uncut diamonds
in the bottom of the tank, there.
该死
Goddamn.
Glenn was right.
You got about 5 million worth in there?
葛兰说得没错，那大概值五百万吧?
Five point two.
五百二十万
看起来就像不起眼的石头
They just look like plain 0l' rocks!
They sure do. You wanna grab 'em?
对，你想抓一把吗?
If I were you, I'd get up and run.
如果换了我是你，我拔腿就溜了
我不能留下美姬  他们会杀了你
- I'm not leaving Midge.
-They're gonna kill you.
If that's my fate then so be it.
I won't leave her. I'm in love with her.
那我就认命了，我不离开她，我爱上她了
- Come on, Jack.
-Good luck, Richard.
算了，杰克  祝你好运，理查
- Come on, Jack.
-They're gonna rape that maid, aren't they?
快点，杰克  他们要强暴那个女佣，是吗
By the look of those guys, the Ripper too.
看样子是
- Then they're gonna kill 'em.
-At least.
然后再把他们干掉  大概是吧
- Tricky motherfucker.
-Are those my suits?
狗娘养的  那些是我的衣服吗
These are my suits. Look at you.
是我的，看看你
你都躲在哪儿了?
Where you been hidin', Dick?
我们成了
We made it, didn't we?
先上车  我要回去
Just get "m the van.
-I'm gem' back 'm.
我和你一起去  在机场和我碰头
- I'm goin' with you.
-Meet me at the airport.
I'll get one of Ripley's cars.
我开瑞利的车来  杰克
The shit about to go down here, you'll be
on the phone with your sister for a month.
你和你老姊大概会在电话里聊这事聊上一个月
我们现在扯平了  这儿
- I'm sayin' we're square.
-Here.
耶
杰克
滚开
Get out of here!
把这玩意拿下来  滚开
- Get that shit off.
-Get your hands off me!
Shut up! Nobody's gonna help you.
闭嘴!没人会来救你
美姬，珠宝究竟在哪里?
Fuck Midge. Where the jewels at, Dick?
- Foley's got them.
-Where the fuck is Foley?
弗理拿去了弗理在哪里?
Midge.
美姬!
(GUN FIRING)
- Midge!
-Sit your punk ass down.
美姬!给我坐下
(GROANS)
猪猡
Son of a bitch!
你走前门，我走后门
Take the front stairs.
I'm gonna take the back.
你没事吧?理查在哪里
- You all right?
-Where's Richard?
He's downstairs. You wait here.
在楼下，在这儿等著
Hold it, asshole. Drop the gun.
不许动，把枪丢下
丢下
把枪放下
Put the damn gun down, now.
马上
(SHOUTING) Put it down!
放下
Stay right there. Don't move. Maurice!
在那儿待著别动，莫瑞
我找到弗理了
I got Foley!
莫瑞
Maurice!
(GUN FIRES)
(GUN CLICKS)
没有多的弹夹可给我用的?
Ain't got another clip I can use, do you?
没有
No, I don't.
- Never shot a gun before, have you?
-Not until recently, no.
从没开过枪吧?对，最近才学会
有点紧张  一点点
- You a little nervous?
-Little bit.
在这种情况下，很可能
A situation like this
has a high potentiality
被这些狗娘养的给逃了
for the common motherfucker to bitch out.
So I figure, why take a chance?
所以我想，为什么要冒险?
Bitch!
婊子
干你娘
Motherfucker!
住手，举起手来
Stop! Put your hands in the air!
(EXCLAIMING)
KAREN: Jack!
杰克?
- KAREN: I know you're up there.
-Shit!
我知道你在上面
呸
- KAREN: Where's Kenneth?
-He's up here.
肯尼在哪里  他在上面
He's dead.
他挂了
算了，杰克，别这样  就当不是我
- Come on, Jack, don't.
-Pretend it's not me.
- You think I'd shoot you?
-If you don't, somebody else will.
你以为我会对你开枪?  你不开，别人也会开
What're you now? A desperado?
你现在算什么?亡命之徒?
- Put the gun down.
-I'm not goin' back.
把枪放下  我不回去坐牢
Don't make me do this. Put the gun down.
不要逼我，把枪放下
浑蛋，杰克，把枪放下
Damn it, Jack, put the gun down!
(SIRENS WAILING)
没有时间了
No more time-outs.
算你赢，杰克
You win, Jack.
(GROANING)
- I can't shoot you.
-You did. You shot me.
我没法射你  你开了，你射中我
You know what I mean.
你知道我的
抱歉，我真希望事情不这样
I'm sorry. I wish things were different.
Airport.
机场
KAREN: They don't know yet if they want to
bring him up on the homicides.
他们还没确定是否要控他杀人罪
I doubt if they will.
They'll just put a detainer on him.
我想不会，他们会把他在关一阵子
When they're through with him here,
he'll go back to Florida.
等审完以后，他会回佛罗里达
MARSHALL: Are you gonna go get him?
你会把他押解回来吗?
KAREN". It's possible. Why?
可能，干嘛
MARSHALL: I was just thinking.
想想而已
You can have a nice time
with him on the ride down,
你可以一路上和他逍遥
picking up where your "interlude" left off,
续上你们之间的那段插曲
then you can throw him in the shithouse.
然后把他扔回监狱
KAREN: He knew what he was doing.
他知道自己在做什么
Nobody forced him to rob banks.
没人逼他抢银行
MARSHALL: My little girl. The tough babe.
我可怜的女儿，真坚强
我稍后再和你连络
MARSHALL: I'll call you later.
再见
MARSHALL: Good-bye.
KAREN: Jack.
杰克
给你一个礼物
I got you a present.
路上用的
Something for the road.
不过，旅途结束后我还是要收回的
I'm gonna have to take it away,
though, soon as the ride is over.
OFFICER: Jack Foley? Meet Hejira Henry.
杰克弗理?来见海极亨利
这个名字很特别
What kind of a name is Hejira?
- It's Islamic.
-What's it stand for?
是回教名字  代表什么?
The "Hejira" was Muhammad's
flight from Mecca in 622.
“海极”是西元622年墨罕默得逃离麦加意思
His flight?
他的逃离? 利文沃的兄弟给我取的名字
Brothers in Leavenworth
gave me that name.
你在和利文沃待过?
You were in Leavenworth?
待过一段日子  什么意思?
- For a time.
-Meaning?
- Meaning, the time came, I left.
-You busted out.
时间到我就走了  你逃跑了
是从自己不愿待的地方离开
I prefer to think of it as an exodus
from an undesirable place.
- How long before you got caught?
-That time?
过多久你又被逮到?那一次吗?
- There were others?
-That was the ninth.
还有多少次啊?那是第九次
The ninth?
第九次?
如果把那次从监狱医院逃走也算的话，就是第十次
Ten if you count that prison
hospital I walked away from.
亨利，你倒跷头不少次  海极
- You done a lot of walkin', Henry.
-Hejira.
Hejira. Now we're off to Glades.
我们现在出发去葛雷兹
好像是吧
It looks that way.
I was supposed to leave
last night with the lady marshal.
我昨天晚上本来应该跟一个女警官走的
不知为什么她要等
For some reason she wanted to wait.
- JACK: She did?
-Guess it's cheaper taking us in one van.
是吗? 我想两人坐车省点钱吧
可能，说不定她以为我们有很多可聊的
Could be. Maybe she thought
we had a lot to talk about.
是吗?聊什么?
Really? Like what?
I don't know. Long ride to Florida.
我不知道，到佛罗里达有好一段路要走